<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" media="screen" href="/~d/styles/rss2full.xsl"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" media="screen" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~d/styles/itemcontent.css"?><rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0" version="2.0">

	<channel>
		<title>TechCrunch</title>
		
		<link>http://www.techcrunch.com</link>
		<description>TechCrunch is a group-edited blog that profiles the companies, products and events defining and transforming the new web.</description>
		<pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2009 06:03:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=2.7.1</generator>
		<language>en</language>
						<image><link>http://www.techcrunch.com</link><url>http://www.techcrunch.com/wp-content/themes/techcrunchmu/images/techcrunch_logo.png</url><title>TechCrunch</title></image><atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/Techcrunch" type="application/rss+xml" /><feedburner:emailServiceId>Techcrunch</feedburner:emailServiceId><feedburner:feedburnerHostname>http://feedburner.google.com</feedburner:feedburnerHostname><feedburner:feedFlare href="http://add.my.yahoo.com/rss?url=http%3A%2F%2Ffeeds.feedburner.com%2FTechcrunch" src="http://us.i1.yimg.com/us.yimg.com/i/us/my/addtomyyahoo4.gif">Subscribe with My Yahoo!</feedburner:feedFlare><feedburner:feedFlare href="http://www.newsgator.com/ngs/subscriber/subext.aspx?url=http%3A%2F%2Ffeeds.feedburner.com%2FTechcrunch" src="http://www.newsgator.com/images/ngsub1.gif">Subscribe with NewsGator</feedburner:feedFlare><feedburner:feedFlare href="http://feeds.my.aol.com/add.jsp?url=http%3A%2F%2Ffeeds.feedburner.com%2FTechcrunch" src="http://o.aolcdn.com/favorites.my.aol.com/webmaster/ffclient/webroot/locale/en-US/images/myAOLButtonSmall.gif">Subscribe with My AOL</feedburner:feedFlare><feedburner:feedFlare href="http://www.bloglines.com/sub/http://feeds.feedburner.com/Techcrunch" src="http://www.bloglines.com/images/sub_modern11.gif">Subscribe with Bloglines</feedburner:feedFlare><feedburner:feedFlare href="http://www.netvibes.com/subscribe.php?url=http%3A%2F%2Ffeeds.feedburner.com%2FTechcrunch" src="http://www.netvibes.com/img/add2netvibes.gif">Subscribe with Netvibes</feedburner:feedFlare><feedburner:feedFlare href="http://fusion.google.com/add?feedurl=http%3A%2F%2Ffeeds.feedburner.com%2FTechcrunch" src="http://buttons.googlesyndication.com/fusion/add.gif">Subscribe with Google</feedburner:feedFlare><feedburner:feedFlare href="http://www.pageflakes.com/subscribe.aspx?url=http%3A%2F%2Ffeeds.feedburner.com%2FTechcrunch" src="http://www.pageflakes.com/ImageFile.ashx?instanceId=Static_4&amp;fileName=ATP_blu_91x17.gif">Subscribe with Pageflakes</feedburner:feedFlare><feedburner:browserFriendly>This is an XML content feed. It is intended to be viewed in a newsreader or syndicated to another site.</feedburner:browserFriendly><atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com" /><item>
			<title>AOL Newsroom Now Has (Wow) 1,500 Writers</title>
			<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/uH73_WCUnKs/</link>
			<comments>http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/29/aol-newsroom-now-has-wow-1500-writers/#comments</comments>
			<pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2009 05:59:50 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Michael Arrington</dc:creator>
			
		<category><![CDATA[Company & Product Profiles]]></category>

		<category><![CDATA[AOL]]></category>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.techcrunch.com/?p=88157</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<img src="http://www.techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/07/mags-215x167.jpg" width="215" height="167" />In June we wrote about <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/06/03/one-vision-for-the-new-aol-redefine-online-content-as-print-magazines-fail/">AOL's evolving "Toyota" strategy</a> to evolve into an online media powerhouse just as the print media world is falling apart. New CEO <a href="http://www.crunchbase.com/person/tim-armstrong">Tim Armstrong</a> hasn't been pinned down on how hard he's betting on this strategy in <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/19/tim-armstrongs-prepares-aol-for-a-fragmenting-web/">recent</a> public <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/23/tim-armstrong-at-fortune-brainstorm-the-future-of-aol/">appearances</a>. But the strategy is clearly kicking into high gear anyway, even as the company prepares for a public spinoff from parent company Time Warner. 

AOL now has 1,500 people writing content across its scores of content sub-brands, we've confirmed. Around 1,000 of those people are working full time for AOL, the rest are freelancing. That's more than double the number that they had creating content a year ago, and by this time next year, we've heard, the plan is to have 2-3x as many people as they do now.

Where is AOL hiring these journalists? From the failing print world. We've obtained a list of hundreds of these individuals, including former journalists at BusinessWeek, New York Times, USA Today, ESPN, Washington Post, Wall Street Journal, Forbes, Consumer Reports, Condé Nast and scores of regional and national newspapers and magazines. A few of them are listed at the end of this report.

From our earlier post describing the media strategy:]]></description>
					<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src='http://cache0.techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/06/mags.jpg'class="snap_nopreview shot" alt="" />In June we wrote about <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/06/03/one-vision-for-the-new-aol-redefine-online-content-as-print-magazines-fail/">AOL&#8217;s evolving &#8220;Toyota&#8221; strategy</a> to evolve into an online media powerhouse just as the print media world is falling apart. New CEO <a href="http://www.crunchbase.com/person/tim-armstrong">Tim Armstrong</a> hasn&#8217;t been pinned down on how hard he&#8217;s betting on this strategy in <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/19/tim-armstrongs-prepares-aol-for-a-fragmenting-web/">recent</a> public <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/23/tim-armstrong-at-fortune-brainstorm-the-future-of-aol/">appearances</a>. But the strategy is clearly kicking into high gear anyway, even as the company prepares for a public spinoff from parent company Time Warner. </p>
<p>AOL now has 1,500 people writing content across its scores of content sub-brands, we&#8217;ve confirmed. Around 1,000 of those people are working full time for AOL, the rest are freelancing. That&#8217;s more than double the number that they had creating content a year ago, and by this time next year, we&#8217;ve heard, the plan is to have 2-3x as many people as they do now.</p>
<p>Where is AOL hiring these journalists? From the failing print world. We&#8217;ve obtained a list of hundreds of these individuals, including former journalists at BusinessWeek, New York Times, USA Today, ESPN, Washington Post, Wall Street Journal, Forbes, Consumer Reports, Condé Nast and scores of regional and national newspapers and magazines. A few of them are listed at the end of this report.</p>
<p>From our earlier post describing the media strategy:</p>
<blockquote><p>But the real opportunity for AOL is to grab marketshare in a relatively open field, say some people close to the company. A contingent of AOL executives are said to be pushing Armstrong to embrace what I&#8217;ve heard is called the &#8220;Toyota strategy&#8221; by building and buying scores of great online media brands. AOL is the &#8220;Toyota&#8221; and the media brands are like the many car models that Toyota successfully pushes - Highlander, Camry, Pious, etc. The analogy isn&#8217;t perfect, but it gives you a good idea of how they&#8217;re thinking of organizing things.</p>
<p>The foundation for this strategy is already firmly in place, and has been since <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2005/10/05/aol-acquires-weblog-inc/">AOL acquired Weblogs, Inc.</a> in 2005 for $25 million or so (that was three AOL CEO&#8217;s ago, when <a href="http://www.crunchbase.com/person/jonathan-miller">Jonathan Miller</a> was running things). All those great Weblogs brands have continued to grow at a breakneck pace.  Sites like Engadget, TUAW and Joystiq are all great niche brands on their own. And AOL has expanded into many other sub-brands through their <a href="http://www.mediaglow.com/">MediaGlow</a> division under <a href="http://www.crunchbase.com/person/bill-wilson">Bill Wilson</a>. </p>
<p><a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/01/12/aol-continues-to-splinter-content-into-anti-portals/">MediaGlow was unveiled</a> a year ago. These are AOL&#8217;s content sites - music, finance, the blogs, and new sites like <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/04/26/aol-launches-online-news-magazine-politicsdaily/">PoliticsDaily</a> and <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/04/24/aols-secret-lovecom/">Love.com</a>. Combined, these sites bring in 76 million unique monthly visitors (Comsore, May 2009). 27 of the <a href="http://technorati.com">Technorati</a> Top 100 blogs are owned by AOL.</p>
<p>The MediaGlow team wants to pick up the pieces of the dying print media business. Advertising is falling off a cliff (billions of dollars in advertising <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/06/02/from-terrible-to-terrifying-newspaper-ad-sales-plummet-26-billion-in-first-quarter/">has evaporated</a>). Combined with the high structural costs of print media (high wages, and well, printing on paper and mailing to readers) and the result is a lot of high quality talent is suddenly willing to take a job in online, even at a much lower salary.</p>
<p>The plan would be to build and buy scores of new brands in every monetizable niche possible. If you see a magazine at the newsstand covering a topic, AOL will have their own online brand for that topic, in blog or other format. They&#8217;ve already got the publishing platform with MediaGlow. New brands can be inserted or built at little marginal operating cost. And the talent is out there for the taking right now.</p></blockquote>
<p>A few of the journalists now working at AOL:</p>
<p>Alex Salkever - formerly Businessweek&#8217;s Technology Editor, now at AOL Daily Finance</p>
<p>Jay Mariotti is a national columnist and commentator for FanHouse.com. He also is a daily panelist on ESPN&#8217;s sports-debate show, &#8220;Around The Horn”, seen Monday-Friday at 5 p.m. ET. Mariotti spent 17 years as a lead sports columnist for the Chicago Sun-Times and has covered every major sporting event &#8212; national and worldwide – numerous times. Mariotti is a member of the Baseball Writers Association of America and is a Hall of Famer voter. He resides in Chicago.</p>
<p>Kevin B. Blackistone is a national columnist and commentator for FanHouse.com. He also is a regular panelist on ESPN&#8217;s daily sports-debate show, &#8220;Around The Horn&#8221;. Blackistone currently serves as the Shirley Povich Chair in Sports Journalism at the Philip Merrill College of Journalism at the University of Maryland. He is the author of the book: “A Gift for Ron: Friendship and Sacrifice On and Off the Gridiron” detailing Everson Walls donating a life-saving kidney to former Cowboys teammate Ron Springs. A former award-winning sports columnist for The Dallas Morning News, he currently resides in Silver Spring, Md.</p>
<p>Greg Couch is a national columnist for FanHouse. Previously, he was at the Chicago Sun-Times as a sports columnist, takeout writer and beat. He also was a sports columnist at the Akron Beacon-Journal and a sports writer at the Wichita Eagle. He received the 2007 and 2008 Lisagor Award as Best Sports Columnist in Chicago and surrounding areas, was featured twice in the Best American Sports Writing and is an APSE award winner. He resides in Chicago.</p>
<p>David Whitley is a national columnist and commentator for FanHouse. Previously, Whitley had been an award-winning columnist at the Orlando Sentinel for 10 years. </p>
<p>Beth Pinsker Gladstone (Editor Walletpop) worked formerly for Inside.com, the Dallas Morning News, Entertainment Weekly, The Independent Film &#038; Video magazine and iVillage.com and her freelance career has encompassed everything from a column at WSJ.com to a stint on staff at Who Wants to Be a Millionaire. </p>
<p>Todd Pruzan (Senior Programming Manager) has been an editor and writer at Condé Nast Portfolio, Details, Blender, Advertising Age, and numerous other places. He has written for publications including The New Yorker and The New York Times and is the author of the 2005 book The Clumsiest People in Europe. </p>
<p>Andrea Chalupa (Associate Producer) most recently wrote and produced videos for Portfolio.com, covering the Sundance Film Festival, the 2008 Presidential Conventions, among others </p>
<p>Mitch Lipka (consumer ally) Investigative journalist for consumer issues, formerly of the Consumer Reports, the Philadelphia Inquirer and other places </p>
<p>Julie Tilsner (lead blogger) More than 20 years as reporter, writer and editor for regional and national publications, including Business Week Magazine and the L.A. Times. Author of four humor books on parenting. Currently a freelance writer for women&#8217;s magazines such as Parenting, American Baby, Redbook and others. </p>
<p>Melinda Henneberger: She spent 10 years as a reporter for the New York Times, in the paper’s Washington and Rome bureaus, and found covering the Vatican a lot like covering Congress, the former having practically invented politics. She is the author of If They Only Listened to Us: What Women Voters Want Politicians to Hear (2007, Simon &#038; Schuster) based on interviews with women in 20 states after the 2004 presidential election. At New York Newsday, and was part of a team that won a Pulitzer Prize for spot news reporting on a subway crash at which she was the first reporter on the scene – at the Union Square station underneath her apartment building.</p>
<p>Carl Cannon: Carl was the DC bureau chief for Reader&#8217;s Digest and for a decade before that, covered the White House for National Journal. Before coming to Washington during the Reagan presidency, he worked for six newspapers over a 20-year span. He has covered every presidential campaign and major political convention since 1984, was honored for his White House coverage by winning the prestigious Gerald R. Ford Prize for Distinguished Reporting of the Presidency and in 2006 received the other top honor on the White House beat, the Aldo Beckman award for “excellence in presidential news coverage.” He is also a past president of the White House Correspondents’ Association. In 2007, Carl was a fellow-in-residence at the Institute of Politics at Harvard&#8217;s John F. Kennedy School of Government.  He authored or co-authored four books.</p>
<p>Jill Lawrence: Jill is a former national political correspondent for USA Today. She has also written about politics for The Associated Press, The Boston Globe, The Atlanta Constitution and other publications.   She has covered every presidential campaign since 1988. Columbia Journalism Review named her one of the top 10 campaign reporters in the country in 2004. She was included in Washingtonian Magazine&#8217;s 2005 list of the 50 best and most influential journalists in Washington .</p>
<p>Walter Shapiro: Walter has covered the last eight presidential campaigns as a columnist and political reporter. Along the way, he has worked for two newspapers (USA Today and the Washington Post), two news weeklies (Time and Newsweek), two monthlies (Esquire and the Washington Monthly) and two online magazines (Salon and Slate). He served as a White House speechwriter for President Jimmy Carter and a special assistant and speechwriter for Secretary of Labor Ray Marshall.  And in 1972, he ran for Congress from Michigan, finishing second in a six-way primary.</p>
<p>Lynn Sweet: Sweet is a frequent guest on MSNBC, CNN and FOX News and other broadcast outlets.  In July 2008, Sweet traveled with Obama’s presidential campaign to Jordan, Israel, Germany, France and England. In 2006 Sweet reported on Obama’s Africa trip, including Obama&#8217;s visit to his father&#8217;s native Kenya. In 2002 Sweet reported from the Middle East as violence between Israelis and Palestinians was deepening. In 1995 she broke the story on perks offered by the Clinton White House to major donors. In 1990, she was among the first journalists in the nation to analyze political ads for accuracy.  Sweet was named a fellow at Harvard University&#8217;s Institute of Politics at the Kennedy School of  Government in Spring, 2004.</p>
<p>Nikhil Hutheesing recently joined DailyFinance as Investing Editor. Formerly, he was at Forbes for 17 years and wrote a top investing newsletter about wireless stocks. </p>
<p>Jonathan Berr is a former reporter with Bloomberg News whose work has appeared in The New York Times, BusinessWeek and The Philadelphia Inquirer. In 2000, he won the Gerald Loeb Award, one of the most prestigious prizes in business journalism.</p>
<p><strong><em>Crunch Network</em></strong>:  <a href="http://www.mobilecrunch.com/">MobileCrunch</a><em> </em>Mobile Gadgets and Applications, Delivered Daily.</p>
<div><a href='http://d.techcrunch.com/ck.php?n=a8e452d3&amp;cb=343' target='_blank'><img src='http://d.techcrunch.com/avw.php?zoneid=38&amp;cb=17&amp;n=a8e452d3' border='0' alt='' /></a></div>
<div><a href='http://d.techcrunch.com/ck.php?n=a9e88cf5&amp;cb=1869' target='_blank'><img src='http://d.techcrunch.com/avw.php?zoneid=13&amp;cb=1719&amp;n=a9e88cf5' border='0' alt='' /></a></div>


<p><a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/9FqoKirKTS6oMh3tMkhwD5cMh1E/0/da"><img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/9FqoKirKTS6oMh3tMkhwD5cMh1E/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"></img></a><br/>
<a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/9FqoKirKTS6oMh3tMkhwD5cMh1E/1/da"><img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/9FqoKirKTS6oMh3tMkhwD5cMh1E/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"></img></a></p><div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=uH73_WCUnKs:w-c0yFcxJqA:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=uH73_WCUnKs:w-c0yFcxJqA:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=uH73_WCUnKs:w-c0yFcxJqA:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=uH73_WCUnKs:w-c0yFcxJqA:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=uH73_WCUnKs:w-c0yFcxJqA:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=uH73_WCUnKs:w-c0yFcxJqA:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/uH73_WCUnKs" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
						<wfw:commentRss>http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/29/aol-newsroom-now-has-wow-1500-writers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
					<feedburner:origLink>http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/29/aol-newsroom-now-has-wow-1500-writers/</feedburner:origLink></item>
				<item>
			<title>M&amp;A Activity Heats Up In July To $9.6 Billion</title>
			<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/8hOXO7g8eDg/</link>
			<comments>http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/29/ma-activity-heats-up-in-july-to-96-billion/#comments</comments>
			<pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2009 04:11:23 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Erick Schonfeld</dc:creator>
			
		<category><![CDATA[Web 2.0 News & Ideas]]></category>

		<category><![CDATA[crunchbase]]></category>

		<category><![CDATA[M&A]]></category>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.techcrunch.com/?p=88092</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<img src="http://www.techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/07/total_aq_monthly-157x200.png" width="157" height="200" />

Whether it's a sign of economic recovery or just investment bankers getting ready to take off the month of August, there's been a lot acquisition activity lately.  In the last week alone, IBM purchased SPSS for <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/28/monster-merger-ibm-buys-spss-for-approx-12-billion/">$1.2 billion</a>, Amazon bought Zappos for <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/22/amazon-buys-zappos/">$928 million</a>, Sprint paid <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/28/sprint-gobbles-up-virgin-mobile-for-483-million/">$483 million</a> for Virgin Mobile, AdKnowledge paid <a href=" http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/26/the-value-of-virtual-currency-the-real-price-of-super-rewards-was-closer-to-50-million/">$50 million</a> for Super Rewards, and Yahoo picked up Xoopit for <a href="  http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/22/why-did-google-let-yahoo-run-off-with-xoopit/">$20 million</a>.

So far in July, the value of the acquisitions we track <a href="http://www.crunchbase.com/acquisitions?page=1">on CrunchBase</a> totals $9.6 billion, which is nearly three times more M&#038;A activity than the $2.6 billion we tracked in June. M&#038;A exits already started to p<a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/22/cautiously-optimistic-crunchbase-q2-report-shows-upticks-in-vc-funding-and-exits/">erk up in the second quarter </a>, according to our latest <a href=" http://www.techcrunch.com/research/">CrunchBase report</a>.  But the increased deal flow on July suggests that corporate buyers are opening up their purse strings even more while acquisition prices are still relatively cheap.]]></description>
					<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://cache0.techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/07/total_aq_monthly.png" class="shot2"/></p>
<p>Whether it&#8217;s a sign of economic recovery or just investment bankers getting ready to take off the month of August, there&#8217;s been a lot acquisition activity lately.  In the last week alone, IBM purchased SPSS for <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/28/monster-merger-ibm-buys-spss-for-approx-12-billion/">$1.2 billion</a>, Amazon bought Zappos for <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/22/amazon-buys-zappos/">$928 million</a>, Sprint paid <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/28/sprint-gobbles-up-virgin-mobile-for-483-million/">$483 million</a> for Virgin Mobile, AdKnowledge paid <a href=" http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/26/the-value-of-virtual-currency-the-real-price-of-super-rewards-was-closer-to-50-million/">$50 million</a> for Super Rewards, and Yahoo picked up Xoopit for <a href="  http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/22/why-did-google-let-yahoo-run-off-with-xoopit/">$20 million</a>.</p>
<p>So far in July, the value of the acquisitions we track <a href="http://www.crunchbase.com/acquisitions?page=1">on CrunchBase</a> totals $9.6 billion, which is nearly three times more M&#038;A activity than the $2.6 billion we tracked in June. M&#038;A exits already started to <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/22/cautiously-optimistic-crunchbase-q2-report-shows-upticks-in-vc-funding-and-exits/">perk up in the second quarter </a>, according to our latest <a href=" http://www.techcrunch.com/research/">CrunchBase report</a>.  But the increased deal flow on July suggests that corporate buyers are opening up their purse strings even more while acquisition prices are still relatively cheap.</p>
<p>But the bargains might not last.  Already, the median acquisition price leaped up to $260 million in July, from $22 million in June.  Most of that jump was due to some very big transactions such as the ones listed above, as well as Agilent&#8217;s $1.5 billion purchase of Varian and Bristol-Myers&#8217; $2.1 billion acquisition of Medarex.  Still, you know what they say about rising tides . . . </p>
<p><img src="http://cache0.techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/07/median_aq_monthly-2.png"/>
<p><strong><em>Crunch Network</em></strong>:  <a href="http://www.mobilecrunch.com/">MobileCrunch</a><em> </em>Mobile Gadgets and Applications, Delivered Daily.</p>
<div><a href='http://d.techcrunch.com/ck.php?n=a8e452d3&amp;cb=1815' target='_blank'><img src='http://d.techcrunch.com/avw.php?zoneid=38&amp;cb=1836&amp;n=a8e452d3' border='0' alt='' /></a></div>
<div><a href='http://d.techcrunch.com/ck.php?n=a9e88cf5&amp;cb=7' target='_blank'><img src='http://d.techcrunch.com/avw.php?zoneid=13&amp;cb=712&amp;n=a9e88cf5' border='0' alt='' /></a></div>


<p><a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/_K8J3hXtz8TEhRpSkpLuErJeyog/0/da"><img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/_K8J3hXtz8TEhRpSkpLuErJeyog/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"></img></a><br/>
<a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/_K8J3hXtz8TEhRpSkpLuErJeyog/1/da"><img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/_K8J3hXtz8TEhRpSkpLuErJeyog/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"></img></a></p><div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=8hOXO7g8eDg:LK3zJ7qS3-I:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=8hOXO7g8eDg:LK3zJ7qS3-I:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=8hOXO7g8eDg:LK3zJ7qS3-I:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=8hOXO7g8eDg:LK3zJ7qS3-I:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=8hOXO7g8eDg:LK3zJ7qS3-I:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=8hOXO7g8eDg:LK3zJ7qS3-I:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/8hOXO7g8eDg" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
						<wfw:commentRss>http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/29/ma-activity-heats-up-in-july-to-96-billion/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
					<feedburner:origLink>http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/29/ma-activity-heats-up-in-july-to-96-billion/</feedburner:origLink></item>
				<item>
			<title>New Twitter Cross-Posts To Facebook Have Users Bewildered. (Update: Facebook Bug To Blame)</title>
			<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/8w4l3YJEw0w/</link>
			<comments>http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/29/new-twitter-cross-posts-to-facebook-have-users-bewildered/#comments</comments>
			<pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2009 02:31:48 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Jason Kincaid</dc:creator>
			
		<category><![CDATA[Company & Product Profiles]]></category>

		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>

		<category><![CDATA[Twitter]]></category>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.techcrunch.com/?p=88132</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<img src="http://www.techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/07/4561v1-max-250x250-215x87.png" width="215" height="87" />Twitter is now seeing dozens of tweets a minute from users reporting that their Twitter updates are being posted as automatic updates to their Facebook profile, apparently without their consent.  The change seems to have happened very recently, and reactions are ranging from surprise to anger.

At this point it isn't clear exactly what's going on — it seems like some users may have installed the official Twitter application at some point and not had it post updates until now.  But others are reporting that they've never installed a Twitter-related app, which makes the situation all the more confusing.  We're reaching out to Twitter and Facebook to find out what the cause is.

My hunch is that these users have previously installed the official Twitter app on Facebook, which has had <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/01/twitters-popular-facebook-app-has-been-broken-or-exploited-for-days/">problems</a> in the past, and used it to occasionally check their Twitter profiles without realizing that it was also meant to auto-post their tweets to Facebook (a bug may have prevented these posts from ever actually appearing).  Now Twitter has fixed the bug, and users don't know what's going on.  We'll update as soon we we know the actual cause.]]></description>
					<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Twitter is now seeing dozens of tweets a minute from users reporting that their Twitter updates are being posted as automatic updates to their Facebook profile, apparently without their consent.  The change seems to have happened very recently, and reactions are ranging from surprise to anger.</p>
<p>At this point it isn&#8217;t clear exactly what&#8217;s going on — it seems like some users may have installed the official Twitter application at some point and not had it post updates until now.  But others are reporting that they&#8217;ve never installed a Twitter-related app, which makes the situation all the more confusing.  We&#8217;re reaching out to Twitter and Facebook to find out what the cause is.</p>
<p>My hunch is that these users have previously installed the official Twitter app on Facebook, which has had <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/01/twitters-popular-facebook-app-has-been-broken-or-exploited-for-days/">problems</a> in the past, and used it to occasionally check their Twitter profiles without realizing that it was also meant to auto-post their tweets to Facebook (a bug may have prevented these posts from ever actually appearing). <del datetime="2009-07-30T06:01:54+00:00"> Now Twitter has fixed the bug, and users don&#8217;t know what&#8217;s going on.  We&#8217;ll update as soon we we know the actual cause.</del> <b>Update:</b> A Facebook bug caused this, see below.</p>
<p>It looks like this may have something to do with Facebook ignoring an application&#8217;s privacy settings.  Under Facebook&#8217;s application privacy page, I&#8217;ve unchecked the box that gives Twitter the ability to post updates to &#8220;Publish recent activity (one line stories) to my wall&#8221;.  However, the updates are still showing up.  We&#8217;re seeing <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/29/new-twitter-cross-posts-to-facebook-have-users-bewildered/#comment-2889346">similar</a> reports from users with the FriendFeed app installed.</p>
<p><b>Update 2</b>: Facebook has given us the following statement:</p>
<blockquote><p>Earlier this evening, a small Facebook bug allowed a handful of apps to publish to the stream on behalf of users who had previously authorized the app. The situation has now been resolved, and all application settings will remain intact for users.
</p></blockquote>
<p><img src="http://cache0.techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/07/picture-731.png"/></p>
<p><img src="http://cache0.techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/07/picture-741.png"/></p>
<p><strong><em>Crunch Network</em></strong>:  <a href="http://www.crunchgear.com">CrunchGear</a><em> </em>drool over the sexiest new gadgets and hardware.</p>
<div><a href='http://d.techcrunch.com/ck.php?n=a8e452d3&amp;cb=693' target='_blank'><img src='http://d.techcrunch.com/avw.php?zoneid=38&amp;cb=1425&amp;n=a8e452d3' border='0' alt='' /></a></div>
<div><a href='http://d.techcrunch.com/ck.php?n=a9e88cf5&amp;cb=591' target='_blank'><img src='http://d.techcrunch.com/avw.php?zoneid=13&amp;cb=1062&amp;n=a9e88cf5' border='0' alt='' /></a></div>


<p><a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/vx8oyDWlO6JtzwF2jR_h1N1tPKI/0/da"><img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/vx8oyDWlO6JtzwF2jR_h1N1tPKI/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"></img></a><br/>
<a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/vx8oyDWlO6JtzwF2jR_h1N1tPKI/1/da"><img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/vx8oyDWlO6JtzwF2jR_h1N1tPKI/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"></img></a></p><div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=8w4l3YJEw0w:Hbug9jkfmro:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=8w4l3YJEw0w:Hbug9jkfmro:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=8w4l3YJEw0w:Hbug9jkfmro:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=8w4l3YJEw0w:Hbug9jkfmro:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=8w4l3YJEw0w:Hbug9jkfmro:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=8w4l3YJEw0w:Hbug9jkfmro:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/8w4l3YJEw0w" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
						<wfw:commentRss>http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/29/new-twitter-cross-posts-to-facebook-have-users-bewildered/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
					<feedburner:origLink>http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/29/new-twitter-cross-posts-to-facebook-have-users-bewildered/</feedburner:origLink></item>
				<item>
			<title>JamLegend’s ‘Guitar Hero For The Web’ Now Lets You Upload And Play Any Song You’d Like</title>
			<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/fusU74PsO9g/</link>
			<comments>http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/29/jamlegends-guitar-hero-for-the-web-now-lets-you-play-any-song-youd-like/#comments</comments>
			<pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2009 02:07:41 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Jason Kincaid</dc:creator>
			
		<category><![CDATA[Company & Product Profiles]]></category>

		<category><![CDATA[JamLegend]]></category>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.techcrunch.com/?p=87985</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.jamlegend.com"><img src="http://www.techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/07/picture-712.png" width="213" height="61" /></a>The Guitar Hero/Rock Band phenomenon is showing no signs of waning, with countless sequels still on the way (including one focused solely on music by The Beatles) and money continuing to pour into the coffers of their respective game publishers.  But gamers are still being forced to live with a problem that's troubled the genre since its formation: you can only play along to songs that publishers have approved, licensed, and then 'mapped out' with note charts to play along to.  Today, they're getting a solution: <a href="http://www.jamlegend.com">JamLegend</a>, the Guitar Hero-like <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2008/08/28/jamlegend-takes-on-guitar-hero-on-the-web-1000-invites/">website</a> that uses your keyboard instead of a plastic guitar, has launched a new feature that lets you play along to any song in your music collection, whenever you'd like.

For those that haven't been exposed to JamLegend before, the site shares a lot of common ground with Guitar Hero.  Gamers load up a song and a flurry of colored dots begin to flow down the screen, with each one corresponding to a differet key on your keyboard.  The experience is less atmospheric than the games you'll find on the consoles, largely because it lacks flashy graphics and plastic guitars, but if you're a Guitar Hero addict looking to get your fix at the office, it's certainly good enough.]]></description>
					<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.jamlegend.com"><img src="http://cache0.techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/07/picture-712.png" class="shot2"/></a>The Guitar Hero/Rock Band phenomenon is showing no signs of waning, with countless sequels still on the way (including one focused solely on music by The Beatles) and money continuing to pour into the coffers of their respective game publishers.  But gamers are still being forced to live with a problem that&#8217;s troubled the genre since its formation: you can only play along to songs that publishers have approved, licensed, and then &#8216;mapped out&#8217; with note charts to play along to.  Today, they&#8217;re getting a solution: <a href="http://www.jamlegend.com">JamLegend</a>, the Guitar Hero-like <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2008/08/28/jamlegend-takes-on-guitar-hero-on-the-web-1000-invites/">website</a> that uses your keyboard instead of a plastic guitar, has launched a new feature that lets you play along to any song in your music collection, whenever you&#8217;d like.</p>
<p>For those that haven&#8217;t been exposed to JamLegend before, the site shares a lot of common ground with Guitar Hero.  Gamers load up a song and a flurry of colored dots begin to flow down the screen, with each one corresponding to a differet key on your keyboard.  The experience is less atmospheric than the games you&#8217;ll find on the consoles, largely because it lacks flashy graphics and plastic guitars, but if you&#8217;re a Guitar Hero addict looking to get your fix at the office, it&#8217;s certainly good enough.</p>
<p>Until now JamLegend has fallen prey to the same problem as Guitar Hero and other console games: if a song wasn&#8217;t in the catalog, you couldn&#8217;t play it.  Now, you can upload any song you&#8217;d like, and using digital signal processing, beat detection, and other automatic analysis, JamLegend takes the song and converts it into a playable track within a few minutes.  Of course, generating a playable track is is one thing — but are they any good?</p>
<p><img src="http://cache0.techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/07/alwayswithme.png"/></p>
<p>After trying out a few tracks, I found the technology to work well, though it isn&#8217;t perfect.  On a standard, professionally-made track, you typically play along to guitar notes and not the accompanying drum beats or vocals.  The auto-generated tracks tend to catch the most prominent sound at any point in the track, which means that sometimes you&#8217;ll find yourself playing elements of each instrument, along with the vocals.  This isn&#8217;t necessarily a bad thing, it&#8217;s just a bit different from what you may be used to.</p>
<p>Because this is a fairly unique feature in the genre, JamLegend is hoping to use it to start monetizing the site.  Users can upload up to five of their own tracks at once, and each week they can swap out one of these for a new one (in other words, there&#8217;s a waiting period before you can add new songs).  If you&#8217;d like to have more songs available at once, the site offers an entry-level premium package for $5 a month, which allows for up to 100 tracks at once, or a $20/month package for 500 songs.</p>
<p>All in all this a solid addition, though I&#8217;m curious if the record industry will have a problem with it.  The only way to add a song to your library is to upload your own copy (the site makes it easy to buy songs you don&#8217;t already own, which is another source of revenue), but we&#8217;ve seen the labels get upset over less.</p>
<p><strong><em>Crunch Network</em></strong>:  <a href="http://www.crunchboard.com">CrunchBoard</a><em> </em>because it&#8217;s time for you to find a new Job2.0</p>
<div><a href='http://d.techcrunch.com/ck.php?n=a8e452d3&amp;cb=1905' target='_blank'><img src='http://d.techcrunch.com/avw.php?zoneid=38&amp;cb=459&amp;n=a8e452d3' border='0' alt='' /></a></div>
<div><a href='http://d.techcrunch.com/ck.php?n=a9e88cf5&amp;cb=608' target='_blank'><img src='http://d.techcrunch.com/avw.php?zoneid=13&amp;cb=437&amp;n=a9e88cf5' border='0' alt='' /></a></div>


<p><a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/g94nlb58-zOKmeW1vlOxbawko-k/0/da"><img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/g94nlb58-zOKmeW1vlOxbawko-k/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"></img></a><br/>
<a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/g94nlb58-zOKmeW1vlOxbawko-k/1/da"><img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/g94nlb58-zOKmeW1vlOxbawko-k/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"></img></a></p><div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=fusU74PsO9g:0EaWVHG5OAg:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=fusU74PsO9g:0EaWVHG5OAg:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=fusU74PsO9g:0EaWVHG5OAg:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=fusU74PsO9g:0EaWVHG5OAg:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=fusU74PsO9g:0EaWVHG5OAg:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=fusU74PsO9g:0EaWVHG5OAg:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/fusU74PsO9g" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
						<wfw:commentRss>http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/29/jamlegends-guitar-hero-for-the-web-now-lets-you-play-any-song-youd-like/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
					<feedburner:origLink>http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/29/jamlegends-guitar-hero-for-the-web-now-lets-you-play-any-song-youd-like/</feedburner:origLink></item>
				<item>
			<title>Is the iPhone Causing Apple to Lose the Plot?</title>
			<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/aldR5qw9Nl4/</link>
			<comments>http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/29/is-the-iphone-causing-apple-to-lose-the-plot/#comments</comments>
			<pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2009 01:40:40 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Nicholas Deleon</dc:creator>
			
		<category><![CDATA[Company & Product Profiles]]></category>

		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>

		<category><![CDATA[iPhone]]></category>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.techcrunch.com/?p=88111</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<img src="http://www.techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/07/cp_1248918040_plot-215x143.jpg" width="215" height="143" />Is Apple losing the plot? I ask this because, having just read <a HREF="http://www.wired.com/threatlevel/2009/07/jailbreak/comment-page-1/#comments">this bollocks</a> (Apple wants to make jailbreaking illegal because it supposedly threatens our nation's cellphone tower infrastructure, and thereby threatens our national security), I've read nothing but well-reasoned, anti-Apple invective. Come, let's explore the phenomenon.

But first: what's going on? The Electronic Frontier Foundation wants to make iPhone jailbreaking 100 percent legal. It's your phone, so why can't you install whatever the hell you want on it? No one tells you what software you can and cannot install on your PC, right? Exactly. Now, Apple doesn't want jailbreaking to given any sort of legal blessing, because, well, Apple is Apple, and AT&#038;T, <a HREF="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/28/can-att-handle-the-iphone/">its incompetent partner in crime</a>, doesn't know if it's coming or going. Want to use <a HREF="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/27/apple-is-growing-rotten-to-the-core-and-its-likely-atts-fault/">Google Voice mobile</a>? Oh, I bet you do, but The Man doesn't want you to. ]]></description>
					<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="http://www.techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/07/cp_1248918040_plot-215x143.jpg" width="215" height="143" />Is Apple losing the plot? I ask this because, having just read <a HREF="http://www.wired.com/threatlevel/2009/07/jailbreak/comment-page-1/#comments">this bollocks</a> (Apple wants to make jailbreaking illegal because it supposedly threatens our nation's cellphone tower infrastructure, and thereby threatens our national security), I've read nothing but well-reasoned, anti-Apple invective. Come, let's explore the phenomenon.

But first: what's going on? The Electronic Frontier Foundation wants to make iPhone jailbreaking 100 percent legal. It's your phone, so why can't you install whatever the hell you want on it? No one tells you what software you can and cannot install on your PC, right? Exactly. Now, Apple doesn't want jailbreaking to given any sort of legal blessing, because, well, Apple is Apple, and AT&#038;T, <a HREF="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/28/can-att-handle-the-iphone/">its incompetent partner in crime</a>, doesn't know if it's coming or going. Want to use <a HREF="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/27/apple-is-growing-rotten-to-the-core-and-its-likely-atts-fault/">Google Voice mobile</a>? Oh, I bet you do, but The Man doesn't want you to. 
<p><a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/ccV2mnpq7EDb278oQK0LGq3fONw/0/da"><img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/ccV2mnpq7EDb278oQK0LGq3fONw/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"></img></a><br/>
<a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/ccV2mnpq7EDb278oQK0LGq3fONw/1/da"><img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/ccV2mnpq7EDb278oQK0LGq3fONw/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"></img></a></p><div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=aldR5qw9Nl4:97aiNSvJZ3Q:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=aldR5qw9Nl4:97aiNSvJZ3Q:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=aldR5qw9Nl4:97aiNSvJZ3Q:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=aldR5qw9Nl4:97aiNSvJZ3Q:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=aldR5qw9Nl4:97aiNSvJZ3Q:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=aldR5qw9Nl4:97aiNSvJZ3Q:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/aldR5qw9Nl4" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
						<wfw:commentRss>http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/29/is-the-iphone-causing-apple-to-lose-the-plot/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
					<feedburner:origLink>http://www.mobilecrunch.com/2009/07/29/is-the-iphone-causing-apple-to-lose-the-plot/</feedburner:origLink></item>
				<item>
			<title>Roger McNamee: Judgment Day</title>
			<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/NSMxEuEW-1E/</link>
			<comments>http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/29/roger-mcnamee-judgment-day/#comments</comments>
			<pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2009 00:39:45 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>MG Siegler</dc:creator>
			
		<category><![CDATA[Company & Product Profiles]]></category>

		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>

		<category><![CDATA[iPhone]]></category>

		<category><![CDATA[iphone 3gs]]></category>

		<category><![CDATA[palm]]></category>

		<category><![CDATA[palm-pre]]></category>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.techcrunch.com/?p=88033</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<img src="http://www.techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/07/mcnajudge-215x162.png" width="215" height="162" />“<em>You know the beautiful thing: June 29, 2009, is the two- year anniversary of the first shipment of the iPhone,</em>” <a href="http://www.crunchbase.com/financial-organization/elevation-partners">Elevation Partners</a> (which owns a huge portion of Palm) co-founder <a href="http://www.crunchbase.com/person/roger-mcnamee">Roger McNamee</a> <a href="http://www.bloomberg.com/apps/news?pid=newsarchive&#38;sid=a2SkDk7Tu5Mw">told Bloomberg</a> in March. “<em>Not one of those people will still be using an iPhone a month later.</em>”

Yes, that would be today.

So how did McNamee's claim turn out? Well, let's put it this way: If there was a foot-in-the-mouth award given every year, no one else would need to apply this year. Hell, it might take the prize for the whole decade. It's a quote of <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/14/how-we-know-chrome-os-will-be-a-hit-steve-ballmer-doesnt-think-so/">Ballmer-level proportions</a>.]]></description>
					<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-88077" title="mcnajudge" src="http://cache0.techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/07/mcnajudge.png" alt="mcnajudge" width="360" height="272" />“<em>You know the beautiful thing: June 29, 2009, is the two- year anniversary of the first shipment of the iPhone,</em>” <a href="http://www.crunchbase.com/financial-organization/elevation-partners">Elevation Partners</a> (which owns a huge portion of Palm) co-founder <a href="http://www.crunchbase.com/person/roger-mcnamee">Roger McNamee</a> <a href="http://www.bloomberg.com/apps/news?pid=newsarchive&amp;sid=a2SkDk7Tu5Mw">told Bloomberg</a> in March. “<em>Not one of those people will still be using an iPhone a month later.</em>”</p>
<p>Yes, that would be today.</p>
<p>So how did McNamee&#8217;s claim turn out? Well, let&#8217;s put it this way: If there was a foot-in-the-mouth award given every year, no one else would need to apply this year. Hell, it might take the prize for the whole decade. It&#8217;s a quote of <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/14/how-we-know-chrome-os-will-be-a-hit-steve-ballmer-doesnt-think-so/">Ballmer-level proportions</a>.</p>
<p>Before I dive into any kind of analysis, I can say right off the bat that McNamee&#8217;s statement is false. Why? Because I bought the original iPhone on June 29, 2007. I am still using an iPhone today.</p>
<p>Something else to think about: Estimates are that Apple sold somewhere between 250,000 to 500,000 iPhones in its first weekend on sale in 2007. The last <a href="http://blogs.barrons.com/techtraderdaily/2009/06/30/palm-pre-sales-topped-300000-in-june-analyst-says/">estimates</a> given for Pre sales was that it sold around 300,000 by the end of June. It&#8217;s entirely possible that there haven&#8217;t even been as many Pres sold so far as there were iPhones sold during its first weekend. That doesn&#8217;t just make McNamee&#8217;s claim look bad — it makes it impossible.</p>
<p>I do not have a Palm Pre, but I have used one quite a few times now. It&#8217;s a great phone. The hardware isn&#8217;t exactly my cup of tea (I don&#8217;t like the keyboard), but there is no denying that the webOS software is very solid. Of course, it&#8217;s subjective, but I would say the Pre is the second-best smartphone on the market today.</p>
<p>But that&#8217;s not what McNamee said. He said, &#8220;<em>Not one of those people will still be using an iPhone a month later.</em>” The claim was laughable <a href="http://digital.venturebeat.com/2009/03/05/palm-investor-puts-his-mouth-where-his-money-is/">at the time</a>, but it&#8217;s even <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/21/probably-not-the-palm-pre-chart-roger-mcnamee-wants-to-see/">more laughable now</a>. He was, of course, implying that once people who bought the original iPhone saw the Pre, all of them would switch since their initial 2-year contracts would be up.</p>
<p>The reality has been much different. Not only is it likely that many of the people who originally bought the iPhone are still using one, but many of them have upgraded once or twice to newer models. And of course, there are millions more iPhone customers that have been added since then. Including millions since the launch of the iPhone 3GS, which was launched <em>after</em> the Pre.</p>
<p><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-88087" title="iphonepre" src="http://cache0.techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/07/iphonepre.png" alt="iphonepre" width="310" height="356" />Speaking of the Pre&#8217;s launch, it took place after McNamee&#8217;s claim, and it sold pretty well out of the gate. But Apple announced the iPhone 3GS a few days later, and as expected, it dampened much of the Pre hype. Sales of the Pre remained decent, but <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/14/analyst-finds-palm-pre-sales-stabilize-at-ho-hum-levels/">not stellar</a>, and have been slowly trailing off ever since.</p>
<p>Contrast that with the iPhone 3GS that sold over <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/06/22/apple-touts-1-million-iphone-3g-s-devices-sold-quotes-steve-jobs/">a million units</a> in just three days after its launch, and has remained red hot. It&#8217;s so hot that Apple has had a <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/21/apple-sold-twice-as-many-iphones-as-macs-last-quarter/">hard time</a> keeping it in stock. The Pre, on the other hand, is widely available, according to recent inventory <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/21/probably-not-the-palm-pre-chart-roger-mcnamee-wants-to-see/">checks</a>.</p>
<p>And while it&#8217;s not entirely fair to compare the two platforms by their app stores, the huge difference cannot be overlooked either. The iPhone launched its App Store a year ago, which was a year after the launch of the first iPhone. So there was already an installed user-base, which is one of the reasons why iPhone app downloads completely <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/06/24/a-million-app-downloads-for-palm-a-million-iphone-3gss-for-apple/">destroy</a> Pre app downloads.</p>
<p>But at the same time, the iPhone App Store launched with 500 apps, the Pre&#8217;s App Catalog has an anemic 32 apps, nearly two months after its launch. The number is so laughably low that when two new apps were launched yesterday, it made <a href="http://www.prethinking.com/home/2009/7/29/breaking-news-2-new-apps-on-app-catalog.html">headlines</a> — for the fact that two new apps finally launched.</p>
<p>This is of course because Palm <a href="http://www.crunchgear.com/2009/07/16/palm-opens-the-mojo-sdk-for-all-new-pre-apps-forthcoming/">only just opened its SDK</a> to the public, the lack of which <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/06/18/the-pre-app-catalog-is-tracking-way-way-behind-apples-app-store-and-its-palms-fault/">really hurt</a> its potential. With it out now, the Pre&#8217;s app ecosystem should grow much more quickly, but it will likely still be a few months before we really start to notice that.</p>
<p>But McNamee knew all of that when he made that statement, and yet, he still said it.</p>
<p>Now, it&#8217;s one thing to tout your own product, but calling out a rival with a comment so asinine, was a poor choice, to say the least. And to Palm&#8217;s credit, they knew it too, which is why they <a href="http://www.prethinking.com/home/2009/3/9/10-clarifications-and-corrections-on-what-mcnamee-said-from.html">sent the SEC a filing</a> with 10 clarifications and corrections about what McNamee said in <em>one</em> interview. Here&#8217;s the correction that relates to this:</p>
<blockquote><p>8. The statement in the second paragraph of the article that &#8220;not one&#8221; person who bought an Apple, Inc. iPhone on the first shipment date &#8220;will still be using an iPhone a month&#8221; after the two-year anniversary of that day is an exaggerated prediction of consumer behavior pattern and is withdrawn.</p></blockquote>
<p>Oh, okay, why don&#8217;t we all just make outrageous claims then send the SEC a note to withdraw them? But that&#8217;s why we&#8217;re here, to hold people&#8217;s feet to the fire when they say idiotic things, even if they petition the SEC to withdraw them.</p>
<p>The fact of the matter is that the iPhone remains the hottest smartphone and may be the <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/04/23/the-state-of-the-iphone-is-strong-very-strong/">hottest platform</a> overall on the planet, right now. Apple has sold around 25 million iPhones. Palm has sold something probably south of a half million Pres — it&#8217;s a number that Sprint wouldn&#8217;t even say during its earnings call. And whatever the number was, it was not enough to stop the service from bleeding customers last quarter.</p>
<p>The Pre, while a nice phone, has a number of things working against it, including Sprint&#8217;s smaller network (though I find it to be much better quality-wise than AT&amp;T&#8217;s <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/28/can-att-handle-the-iphone/">awful network</a>), and the lack of a robust app ecosystem right now. But both of those should change shortly. I already spoke to the app problem, but Verizon has also announced that the Pre will be on its network sometime in early 2010. That will be big, I imagine.</p>
<p><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-88085" title="schiller-palm-wwdc" src="http://cache0.techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/07/schiller-palm-wwdc.png" alt="schiller-palm-wwdc" width="365" height="259" />But will it be iPhone-killing big? No, of course not. There is plenty of room for many smartphones on the market, you&#8217;d have to imagine that even McNamee knows that. I think his iPhone-envy just got the best of him with such a statement. And that was interesting because it added more fuel to the fire of the Apple/Palm rivalry, which was already an interesting one.</p>
<p>Palm has no shortage of ex-Apple employees now working for it, including newly appointed CEO Jon Rubenstein, who used to head Apple&#8217;s iPod and Mac divisions. And now they&#8217;re caught up with this <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/06/16/apple-yeah-about-that-palm-pre-itunes-sync-feature/">cat</a>-and-<a href="http://www.mobilecrunch.com/2009/07/23/palm-releases-webos-110-updated-fixes-itunes-syncing/">mouse</a> game with Apple to make iTunes syncing work for the Pre.</p>
<p>The Pre is also the first mobile device since the iPhone to use multi-touch, something which brought out some interesting statements from Apple about protecting their intellectual property. There have been no lawsuits on that front, but we can probably safely assume that Apple looked into it, and probably isn&#8217;t too happy that it apparently cannot push for legal action.</p>
<p>Then there was the <a href="http://www.businessinsider.com/palm-takes-a-bite-out-of-apple-with-full-page-ad-in-the-nyt-2009-6">ad that Sprint made</a> for the Pre, with an eaten apple (which also spoke to the first wave of expiring iPhone contracts). And then there was Apple trash-talking the Pre&#8217;s small app store size during its WWDC keynote. &#8220;<em>And somebody else. I can’t quite read it. It’s small</em>,&#8221; is what Apple&#8217;s Phil Schiller said. (The chart he&#8217;s referring to is above.)</p>
<p>But Apple can talk for now, it has earned that privilege by running laps around its rivals with its smartphone and App Store. Palm, has not. And they look bad today thanks to McNamee.</p>
<p><strong><em>Crunch Network</em></strong>:  <a href="http://www.mobilecrunch.com/">MobileCrunch</a><em> </em>Mobile Gadgets and Applications, Delivered Daily.</p>
<div><a href='http://d.techcrunch.com/ck.php?n=a8e452d3&amp;cb=613' target='_blank'><img src='http://d.techcrunch.com/avw.php?zoneid=38&amp;cb=975&amp;n=a8e452d3' border='0' alt='' /></a></div>
<div><a href='http://d.techcrunch.com/ck.php?n=a9e88cf5&amp;cb=1069' target='_blank'><img src='http://d.techcrunch.com/avw.php?zoneid=13&amp;cb=1866&amp;n=a9e88cf5' border='0' alt='' /></a></div>


<p><a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/hva_1r10x49GW_dbq3c-11BsEfk/0/da"><img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/hva_1r10x49GW_dbq3c-11BsEfk/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"></img></a><br/>
<a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/hva_1r10x49GW_dbq3c-11BsEfk/1/da"><img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/hva_1r10x49GW_dbq3c-11BsEfk/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"></img></a></p><div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=NSMxEuEW-1E:UVguRHihKB4:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=NSMxEuEW-1E:UVguRHihKB4:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=NSMxEuEW-1E:UVguRHihKB4:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=NSMxEuEW-1E:UVguRHihKB4:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=NSMxEuEW-1E:UVguRHihKB4:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=NSMxEuEW-1E:UVguRHihKB4:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/NSMxEuEW-1E" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
						<wfw:commentRss>http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/29/roger-mcnamee-judgment-day/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
					<feedburner:origLink>http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/29/roger-mcnamee-judgment-day/</feedburner:origLink></item>
				<item>
			<title>Yahoo Shareholders Transfer $2.9 Billion To Microsoft Shareholders</title>
			<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/sNMDPu_die0/</link>
			<comments>http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/29/yahoo-shareholders-transfer-29-billion-to-microsoft-shareholders/#comments</comments>
			<pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2009 22:25:47 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Michael Arrington</dc:creator>
			
		<category><![CDATA[Company & Product Profiles]]></category>

		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>

		<category><![CDATA[Yahoo]]></category>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.techcrunch.com/?p=88049</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<img src="http://www.techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/07/yahoodown-215x167.jpg" width="215" height="167" />Anyone wondering who got the <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/29/yahoo-got-binged/">better deal</a> today (my detailed thoughts later) need only look at the stock movements of <a href="http://www.crunchbase.com/company/yahoo">Yahoo</a> and <a href="http://www.crunchbase.com/company/microsoft">Microsoft</a>. Yahoo <a href="http://www.google.com/finance?q=yahoo">dipped</a> 12.08% to $15.14, knocking $2.91 billion off their market cap. Microsoft <a href="http://www.google.com/finance?q=microsoft">gained</a> 1.41% to $23.80, adding...$2.94 billion to their market cap.

So net/net about $30 million in new value was created today by the market, All of that plus everything Yahoo lost went to Microsoft. Yahoo got Binged, to the tune of $2.9 Billion. <a href="http://twitter.com/arrington/status/2917969732">Oops</a>.

Our complete coverage of the deal is <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/tag/yahoo/">here</a>.
]]></description>
					<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src='http://cache0.techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/07/yahoodown.jpg'class="snap_nopreview shot" alt="" />Anyone wondering who got the <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/29/yahoo-got-binged/">better deal</a> today (my detailed thoughts later) need only look at the stock movements of <a href="http://www.crunchbase.com/company/yahoo">Yahoo</a> and <a href="http://www.crunchbase.com/company/microsoft">Microsoft</a>. Yahoo <a href="http://www.google.com/finance?q=yahoo">dipped</a> 12.08% to $15.14, knocking $2.91 billion off their market cap. Microsoft <a href="http://www.google.com/finance?q=microsoft">gained</a> 1.41% to $23.80, adding&#8230;$2.94 billion to their market cap.</p>
<p>So net/net about $30 million in new value was created today by the market, All of that plus everything Yahoo lost went to Microsoft. Yahoo got Binged, to the tune of $2.9 Billion. <a href="http://twitter.com/arrington/status/2917969732">Oops</a>.</p>
<p>Our complete coverage of the deal is <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/tag/yahoo/">here</a>.</p>
<p><strong><em>Crunch Network</em></strong>:  <a href="http://www.crunchbase.com">CrunchBase</a><em> </em>the free database of technology companies, people, and investors</p>
<div><a href='http://d.techcrunch.com/ck.php?n=a8e452d3&amp;cb=1702' target='_blank'><img src='http://d.techcrunch.com/avw.php?zoneid=38&amp;cb=694&amp;n=a8e452d3' border='0' alt='' /></a></div>
<div><a href='http://d.techcrunch.com/ck.php?n=a9e88cf5&amp;cb=1453' target='_blank'><img src='http://d.techcrunch.com/avw.php?zoneid=13&amp;cb=319&amp;n=a9e88cf5' border='0' alt='' /></a></div>


<p><a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/VVh2tzpGRfU7s1Dk7xClSlqg0Gw/0/da"><img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/VVh2tzpGRfU7s1Dk7xClSlqg0Gw/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"></img></a><br/>
<a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/VVh2tzpGRfU7s1Dk7xClSlqg0Gw/1/da"><img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/VVh2tzpGRfU7s1Dk7xClSlqg0Gw/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"></img></a></p><div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=sNMDPu_die0:TyCaATfZRn4:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=sNMDPu_die0:TyCaATfZRn4:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=sNMDPu_die0:TyCaATfZRn4:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=sNMDPu_die0:TyCaATfZRn4:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=sNMDPu_die0:TyCaATfZRn4:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=sNMDPu_die0:TyCaATfZRn4:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/sNMDPu_die0" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
						<wfw:commentRss>http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/29/yahoo-shareholders-transfer-29-billion-to-microsoft-shareholders/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
					<feedburner:origLink>http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/29/yahoo-shareholders-transfer-29-billion-to-microsoft-shareholders/</feedburner:origLink></item>
				<item>
			<title>AT&amp;T: Don’t Blame Us For The iPhone’s Google Voice Ban</title>
			<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/S2GZaCaJGUA/</link>
			<comments>http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/29/att-dont-blame-us-for-the-iphones-google-voice-ban/#comments</comments>
			<pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2009 22:20:04 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Jason Kincaid</dc:creator>
			
		<category><![CDATA[Company & Product Profiles]]></category>

		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>

		<category><![CDATA[AT&T]]></category>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.techcrunch.com/?p=87997</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<img src="http://www.techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/07/untitled-4-150x200.png" width="150" height="200" />The <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/28/best-comment-ever/">outcry</a> over the <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/27/apple-is-growing-rotten-to-the-core-and-its-likely-atts-fault/">Google Voice ban</a> on the App Store is still going strong, with hundreds of news stories, developer <a href="http://www.riverturn.com/blog/?p=455">posts</a>, and complaints putting the story in and out of Twitter's top trends for nearly three days running.  Much of the <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/28/can-att-handle-the-iphone/">blame</a> has been directed at AT&#038;T, over beliefs that the carrier forced Apple's hand in its decision to ban the applications.  Now it looks like AT&#038;T believes it's been wrongly accused, and it's beginning to take a stand for itself.

Last time we reached out to AT&#038;T to comment on the story, the company gave TechCrunch writer MG Siegler a very blunt and brief statement:


<blockquote>"Nope – Apple is the one who can talk about their App Store."
</blockquote>


But today, the company has begun sending out more detailed messages to some of the frustrated customers who have been voicing their complaints.  The message below was written by Glenn Lurie, AT&#038;T's President of Emerging Devices and Resale.
]]></description>
					<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://cache0.techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/07/untitled-4.png" class="shot2"/>The <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/28/best-comment-ever/">outcry</a> over the <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/27/apple-is-growing-rotten-to-the-core-and-its-likely-atts-fault/">Google Voice ban</a> on the App Store is still going strong, with hundreds of news stories, developer <a href="http://www.riverturn.com/blog/?p=455">posts</a>, and complaints putting the story in and out of Twitter&#8217;s top trends for nearly three days running.  Much of the <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/28/can-att-handle-the-iphone/">blame</a> has been directed at AT&#038;T, over beliefs that the carrier forced Apple&#8217;s hand in its decision to ban the applications.  Now it looks like AT&#038;T believes it&#8217;s been wrongly accused, and it&#8217;s beginning to take a stand for itself.</p>
<p>Last time we reached out to AT&#038;T to comment on the story, the company gave TechCrunch writer MG Siegler a very blunt and brief statement:</p>
<blockquote><p>&#8220;Nope – Apple is the one who can talk about their App Store.&#8221;
</p></blockquote>
<p>But today, the company has begun sending out more detailed messages to some of the frustrated customers who have been voicing their complaints.  The message below was written by Glenn Lurie, AT&#038;T&#8217;s President of Emerging Devices and Resale.</p>
<blockquote><p>Your letter concerning Apple’s decision on the Google Voice iPhone app was forwarded to me since I work closely with Apple.</p>
<p>While we’re very proud to offer the iPhone 3GS along with the thousands of apps available through the App Store, AT&#038;T does not manage the App Store – and we are not involved in the approval process for apps in the App Store.  I recommend in this particular case that you express your concerns to Apple.</p>
<p>I’m glad you’re enjoying your iPhone and hope that you continue to be an AT&#038;T customer.  We appreciate and value your business.</p>
<p>Sincerely,<br />
Glenn Lurie</p>
</blockquote>
<p>AT&#038;T&#8217;s stance is no longer that it can&#8217;t talk about the App Store — it&#8217;s that it doesn&#8217;t <i>manage</i> the App Store, and that any concerns about this case should be directed at Apple.  Of course, the note leaves plenty of wiggle room for AT&#038;T.  The company may not be necessarily &#8220;managing&#8221; the approval process, but it could easily be the whispering in the ears of the people who do.  And to say that AT&#038;T isn&#8217;t involved at all seems highly unlikely as well — why would Apple cripple apps like Sling were it not over bandwidth concerns voiced by AT&#038;T?  Still, there must be some reason why AT&#038;T is beginning to change its tune.  AT&#038;T would be foolish to paint a bulls-eye on Apple as it tries to extend its <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/04/14/shocker-att-wants-to-keep-keep-sitting-on-its-golden-egg-the-iphone/">incredibly valuable</a> exclusive iPhone contract, but it&#8217;s doing what it can to deflect a few of the blows coming from its frustrated customers.</p>
<p>We followed up on the letter above by getting in touch with AT&#038;T, at which point an AT&#038;T spokesman said that the company stood by what Lurie had written and that we should contact Apple for any further information.  Apple spokesman Steve Dowling refused to comment on the matter.  Our brief conversation, which consisted largely of &#8220;we haven&#8217;t made any comment on that&#8221; responses, included this gem:</p>
<blockquote><p>JK: Are you planning to comment?<br />
SD: We haven&#8217;t made any comment on that.</p></blockquote>
<p>So where does the blame truly lie? It&#8217;s unlikely we&#8217;ll ever get a straight answer.  <a href="http://www.daringfireball.com">Daring Fireball&#8217;s</a> John Gruber has <a href="http://daringfireball.net/2009/07/google_voice#update-13:40">cited</a> a reliable source in saying that it was &#8220;AT&#038;T that objected to Google Voice apps for the iPhone. It’s that simple.&#8221;  And I myself <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/27/apple-is-growing-rotten-to-the-core-and-its-likely-atts-fault/">suspect</a> that the blame lies largely with AT&#038;T.  But others, like <a href="http://gigaom.com/2009/07/28/google-voice-iphone/">Om Malik</a>, believe that Apple should be bearing the brunt of the blame.</p>
<p>But in the end, users don&#8217;t really care who is to blame, provided the issue gets resolved quickly.  If that doesn&#8217;t happen, developers will continue to lose faith in the  App Store&#8217;s <a href="http://www.techcrunchit.com/2008/07/15/the-new-apple-walled-garden/">walled garden</a> approach.  Apple will lose its glossy luster, and some will seek lusher platforms where they&#8217;re sure they can actually release the applications they&#8217;ve spent months building.  The iPhone may be dominating this space now, but we&#8217;re really only about two years into this new era of smart phones — it&#8217;s a bit early for Apple to be embittering developers with such regularity.</p>
<p><i>Thanks to Jason Walke for the tip.</i></p>
<p><strong><em>Crunch Network</em></strong>:  <a href="http://www.crunchboard.com">CrunchBoard</a><em> </em>because it&#8217;s time for you to find a new Job2.0</p>
<div><a href='http://d.techcrunch.com/ck.php?n=a8e452d3&amp;cb=1934' target='_blank'><img src='http://d.techcrunch.com/avw.php?zoneid=38&amp;cb=616&amp;n=a8e452d3' border='0' alt='' /></a></div>
<div><a href='http://d.techcrunch.com/ck.php?n=a9e88cf5&amp;cb=1592' target='_blank'><img src='http://d.techcrunch.com/avw.php?zoneid=13&amp;cb=998&amp;n=a9e88cf5' border='0' alt='' /></a></div>


<p><a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/5KU9w3AxzSXg-QOgTPhiEAq5q6A/0/da"><img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/5KU9w3AxzSXg-QOgTPhiEAq5q6A/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"></img></a><br/>
<a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/5KU9w3AxzSXg-QOgTPhiEAq5q6A/1/da"><img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/5KU9w3AxzSXg-QOgTPhiEAq5q6A/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"></img></a></p><div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=S2GZaCaJGUA:Lz57WmDrtv0:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=S2GZaCaJGUA:Lz57WmDrtv0:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=S2GZaCaJGUA:Lz57WmDrtv0:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=S2GZaCaJGUA:Lz57WmDrtv0:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=S2GZaCaJGUA:Lz57WmDrtv0:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=S2GZaCaJGUA:Lz57WmDrtv0:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/S2GZaCaJGUA" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
						<wfw:commentRss>http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/29/att-dont-blame-us-for-the-iphones-google-voice-ban/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
					<feedburner:origLink>http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/29/att-dont-blame-us-for-the-iphones-google-voice-ban/</feedburner:origLink></item>
				<item>
			<title>Yahoo Got Binged</title>
			<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/rDSMeTS8irE/</link>
			<comments>http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/29/yahoo-got-binged/#comments</comments>
			<pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2009 20:48:53 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Erick Schonfeld</dc:creator>
			
		<category><![CDATA[Company & Product Profiles]]></category>

		<category><![CDATA[Web 2.0 News & Ideas]]></category>

		<category><![CDATA[bing]]></category>

		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>

		<category><![CDATA[Yahoo]]></category>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.techcrunch.com/?p=87974</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<img src="http://www.techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/07/bing-is-taking-over-yhoo-215x114.jpg" width="215" height="114" />

Today, Yahoo died as a search engine.  If the <a href=" http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/29/microsoft-yahoo-search-deal-the-most-important-facts-and-some-opinion/">deal with Microsoft</a> is approved, what will replace it will be <a href="http://www.bing.com/">Bing</a>, the search engine that Microsoft <a href=" http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/06/01/apparently-bing-is-something-of-a-hit/">launched</a> only two months ago.  Within a few months time, Microsoft will go from owning 8 percent of the U.S. search market to 28 percent (comScore). That is still less than half of Google's 65 percent, but it could give Microsoft a fighting chance in the search wars against Google.

While the agreement was a long time coming, Bing was the cherry on top, so to speak.  Earlier today, I spoke with the two executives who oversaw the negotiations for both sides, Yahoo EVP <a href="http://www.crunchbase.com/person/hilary-schneider">Hillary Schneider</a> and Microsoft SVP <a href="http://www.crunchbase.com/person/yusuf-mehdi">Yusuf Mehdi</a>.  I asked how big an impact Bing's sudden success had on bringing the deal to a close. ]]></description>
					<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://cache0.techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/07/bing-is-taking-over-yhoo.jpg"/></p>
<p>Today, Yahoo died as a search engine.  If the <a href=" http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/29/microsoft-yahoo-search-deal-the-most-important-facts-and-some-opinion/">deal with Microsoft</a> is approved, what will replace it will be <a href="http://www.bing.com/">Bing</a>, the search engine that Microsoft <a href=" http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/06/01/apparently-bing-is-something-of-a-hit/">launched</a> only two months ago.  Within a few months time, Microsoft will go from owning 8 percent of the U.S. search market to 28 percent (comScore). That is still less than half of Google&#8217;s 65 percent, but it could give Microsoft a fighting chance in the search wars against Google.</p>
<p>While the agreement was a long time coming, Bing was the cherry on top, so to speak.  Earlier today, I spoke with the two executives who oversaw the negotiations for both sides, Yahoo EVP <a href="http://www.crunchbase.com/person/hilary-schneider">Hillary Schneider</a> and Microsoft SVP <a href="http://www.crunchbase.com/person/yusuf-mehdi">Yusuf Mehdi</a>.  I asked how big an impact Bing&#8217;s sudden success had on bringing the deal to a close. &#8220;Seeing Bing as a live experience was a nice assurance,&#8221; says Schneider, &#8220;but did not change our rationale or timing.  This was a conversation that went on over several months.  Bing was introduced after we had material momentum in how we wanted to approach this partnership.&#8221;</p>
<p>Yet Bing was able to gain market share in its very first month, and it <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/15/bing-gains-some-search-share-from-yahoo/">took it from Yahoo</a>, not Google. And Bing is just going to get better. Yahoo faced the very real prospect of market share erosion from below as well as from above.  Now in one fell swoop, Microsoft will control all of Yahoo&#8217;s search volume. In a <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/29/bartz-on-bing-seearch-deal-everyone-wants-a-real-alternative-live-notes/">conference call today</a>, Steve Ballmer explained how important market share is in search:</p>
<blockquote><p>Do we think we will have better algorithms for relevance?  Yes we do. There is a feedback loop in search. the more searches you serve, the more you learn about what people click on. Scale drives knowledge.  There is a return to scale from seeing that much activity [that is more] than Yahoo or MSFT see independently</p></blockquote>
<p>Microsoft will measure the success of this deal in two ways: increased market share with advertisers and increased market share with consumers.  When I asked Mehdi what success would look like a couple years out, he defines it in terms of &#8220;shares of queries and spends.&#8221;  Even before mentioning gaining share with consumers, he says: &#8220;Success is a smooth transition for advertisers as they shift more share of wallet from traditional media and competitors to get the better ROI.&#8221;  </p>
<p>Microsoft will also become the new home for Yahoo&#8217;s search technologies.  That is a good thing because even before this deal was announced, the spirit of technology innovation at Yahoo which produced  projects such as Yahoo Boss and Search Monkey seems to have <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/05/19/yahoo-search-as-we-know-it-is-over/">fizzled</a>.  These efforts will now be passed on to Microsoft.  The fortunate news is that Mehdi says he wants to keep those projects alive.  &#8220;For Search Monkey and Boss, we will integrate that technology and determine how to take that forward.  There is a lot of goodness there.&#8221;  At least Microsoft knows a good developer platform when it sees one.</p>
<p>So the deal is good for Microsoft.  It puts them in the game, and they didn&#8217;t even have to pay $1 billion upfront.  But is it good for Yahoo?  </p>
<p>Instead of that upfront payment, Yahoo is getting 88 percent of search advertising revenues on Yahoo-owned sites every year for the next five years (at which point the so-called TAC rate will be renegotiated for the last five years of the deal).  &#8220;This is a materially higher TAC than any of the <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2008/06/14/hey-microsoft-how-bout-we-do-that-first-deal-you-offered/">previous arrangements</a>,&#8221; says Schneider.  But it&#8217;s also not much higher than what big affiliates like AOL are believed to be getting from Google today.  And Yahoo needs to keep paying its sales force, but can only keep 88 percent of the revenues they generate.  (Although there are some revenue-per-search guarantees baked into the deal to protect Yahoo on the downside).</p>
<p>Investors <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/29/wall-streets-reaction-to-the-microsoft-yahoo-search-deal-not-good/">aren&#8217;t thrilled</a> with the deal, and it is not just because they tend to value cash over potential.  This is a ten-year arrangement between two lumbering giants that is filled with execution risk.  It is a very complicated deal.  Yahoo&#8217;s sales team has enough trouble communicating with its own engineers.  Now they have to learn how to talk to Microsoft&#8217;s.</p>
<p>The two companies will work hard to pull this off.  Their futures depend on it.  And the deal is structured in a way that makes sure both sides make more money the more searches and advertising dollars Bing generates.  Getting to that ideal state, though, won&#8217;t be easy.  In the meantime, as they work through all of the implementation issues, Google could strengthen its position and take even more share.  </p>
<p>No matter what happens, Yahoo just took itself out of the search game.  It got Binged. </p>
<p><strong><em>Crunch Network</em></strong>:  <a href="http://www.crunchgear.com">CrunchGear</a><em> </em>drool over the sexiest new gadgets and hardware.</p>
<div><a href='http://d.techcrunch.com/ck.php?n=a8e452d3&amp;cb=521' target='_blank'><img src='http://d.techcrunch.com/avw.php?zoneid=38&amp;cb=1127&amp;n=a8e452d3' border='0' alt='' /></a></div>
<div><a href='http://d.techcrunch.com/ck.php?n=a9e88cf5&amp;cb=517' target='_blank'><img src='http://d.techcrunch.com/avw.php?zoneid=13&amp;cb=864&amp;n=a9e88cf5' border='0' alt='' /></a></div>


<p><a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/jC-SyTXvE9ZCqS-HO8ueozKD6pg/0/da"><img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/jC-SyTXvE9ZCqS-HO8ueozKD6pg/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"></img></a><br/>
<a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/jC-SyTXvE9ZCqS-HO8ueozKD6pg/1/da"><img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/jC-SyTXvE9ZCqS-HO8ueozKD6pg/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"></img></a></p><div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=rDSMeTS8irE:dT-wjKetjfo:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=rDSMeTS8irE:dT-wjKetjfo:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=rDSMeTS8irE:dT-wjKetjfo:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=rDSMeTS8irE:dT-wjKetjfo:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=rDSMeTS8irE:dT-wjKetjfo:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=rDSMeTS8irE:dT-wjKetjfo:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/rDSMeTS8irE" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
						<wfw:commentRss>http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/29/yahoo-got-binged/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
					<feedburner:origLink>http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/29/yahoo-got-binged/</feedburner:origLink></item>
				<item>
			<title>The Hangover: AOL Gives Time Warner’s Quarterly Results A Headache, Again</title>
			<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/xu-b549cdKE/</link>
			<comments>http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/29/the-hangover-time-warners-q2-results-feature-a-lot-of-goodbye-aol-talk/#comments</comments>
			<pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2009 18:30:50 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>MG Siegler</dc:creator>
			
		<category><![CDATA[Company & Product Profiles]]></category>

		<category><![CDATA[AOL]]></category>

		<category><![CDATA[Time-Warner]]></category>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.techcrunch.com/?p=87975</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<img src="http://www.techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/07/the-hangover-01-215x143.jpg" width="215" height="143" />Time Warner released it<a href="http://finance.yahoo.com/news/Time-Warner-Inc-Reports-bw-4243096883.html?x=0&#38;.v=1"> second quarter results</a> today, and the numbers aren't good. Overall, revenue was down 9% versus the year-ago period as poor results from the publishing, film and yes, AOL dragged down the numbers for all. CEO <a href="http://www.crunchbase.com/person/jeff-bewkes">Jeff Bewkes</a> remarks are telling:
<blockquote>At the same time, we’re continuing the reshaping of Time Warner that we started last year. We’re on track to spin off AOL to our stockholders around the end of the year. Separating AOL will benefit both companies – enabling Time Warner to concentrate fully on our core content businesses and improving AOL’s operational and strategic flexibility.</blockquote>
That's three AOL mentions in three sentences. Clearly, Time Warner is happy to let everyone know that it will only have a couple more quarters of dealing with that division's nosedive.]]></description>
					<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-87977" title="the-hangover-01" src="http://cache0.techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/07/the-hangover-01.jpg" alt="the-hangover-01" width="334" height="222" />Time Warner released it<a href="http://finance.yahoo.com/news/Time-Warner-Inc-Reports-bw-4243096883.html?x=0&amp;.v=1"> second quarter results</a> today, and the numbers aren&#8217;t good. Overall, revenue was down 9% versus the year-ago period as poor results from the publishing, film and yes, AOL dragged down the numbers for all. CEO <a href="http://www.crunchbase.com/person/jeff-bewkes">Jeff Bewkes</a> remarks are telling:</p>
<blockquote><p>At the same time, we’re continuing the reshaping of Time Warner that we started last year. We’re on track to spin off AOL to our stockholders around the end of the year. Separating AOL will benefit both companies – enabling Time Warner to concentrate fully on our core content businesses and improving AOL’s operational and strategic flexibility.</p></blockquote>
<p>That&#8217;s three AOL mentions in three sentences. Clearly, Time Warner is happy to let everyone know that it will only have a couple more quarters of dealing with that division&#8217;s nosedive.</p>
<p>How bad was AOL this quarter? Revenues dropped 24%, to $804 million, versus the year-ago period. The service saw a 21% decrease in advertising revenues, attributable to both display and search ads on its own sites, as well as on third-party sites using its platform.</p>
<p>And the loss of dial-up subscribers continues to hurt the company. It lost over a half million in this past quarter, and some 2.3 million from the year-ago period. Revenues from subscriptions declined 27% from the year-ago period.</p>
<p>In preparation for the <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/05/27/time-warner-to-decide-on-aol-spinoff-at-thursday-board-meeting-its-a-done-deal/">AOL spin-off</a>, Google recently sold back its 5% stake in the company, at <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/27/google-sells-back-its-stake-in-aol-there-goes-700-million/">a $700 million discount</a> from its initial $1 billion investment. However, thanks to the search deal over these past several years, it looks as if Google was much closer to break-even on the deal.</p>
<p>And while AOL&#8217;s numbers were awful, Time Warner&#8217;s print and film divisions hardly fared better. The print division headed up by Time, saw a 26% decrease in ad revenue from the year-ago period, and an 18% decrease in subscription revenue.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, the film division was hurt by the slide in DVD sales. While movies like <em>The Hangover</em> exceeded expectations at the box office, those profits were wiped out by DVD numbers being down across the board.</p>
<p>Highlighting <em>The Hangover</em> in the results is interesting. One could say Time Warner&#8217;s experience with AOL these past several years after the $164 billion mega (or perhaps &#8220;drunken&#8221;) merger in 2001 (remember, it was AOL that actually bought Time Warner at the time), has been similar to <em>The Hangover</em>. Based on the repurchasing price Time Warner paid for Google&#8217;s AOL stock, AOL is now worth less than $6 billion.</p>
<p><img src="http://cache0.techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/07/aol-slides-2q09.jpg"/></p>
<p><strong><em>Crunch Network</em></strong>:  <a href="http://www.mobilecrunch.com/">MobileCrunch</a><em> </em>Mobile Gadgets and Applications, Delivered Daily.</p>
<div><a href='http://d.techcrunch.com/ck.php?n=a8e452d3&amp;cb=1145' target='_blank'><img src='http://d.techcrunch.com/avw.php?zoneid=38&amp;cb=386&amp;n=a8e452d3' border='0' alt='' /></a></div>
<div><a href='http://d.techcrunch.com/ck.php?n=a9e88cf5&amp;cb=583' target='_blank'><img src='http://d.techcrunch.com/avw.php?zoneid=13&amp;cb=960&amp;n=a9e88cf5' border='0' alt='' /></a></div>


<p><a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/PbE-aJjM8c53IUio0VXR45-74Is/0/da"><img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/PbE-aJjM8c53IUio0VXR45-74Is/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"></img></a><br/>
<a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/PbE-aJjM8c53IUio0VXR45-74Is/1/da"><img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/PbE-aJjM8c53IUio0VXR45-74Is/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"></img></a></p><div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=xu-b549cdKE:zgnojDsFA5A:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=xu-b549cdKE:zgnojDsFA5A:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=xu-b549cdKE:zgnojDsFA5A:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=xu-b549cdKE:zgnojDsFA5A:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=xu-b549cdKE:zgnojDsFA5A:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=xu-b549cdKE:zgnojDsFA5A:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/xu-b549cdKE" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
						<wfw:commentRss>http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/29/the-hangover-time-warners-q2-results-feature-a-lot-of-goodbye-aol-talk/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
					<feedburner:origLink>http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/29/the-hangover-time-warners-q2-results-feature-a-lot-of-goodbye-aol-talk/</feedburner:origLink></item>
				<item>
			<title>Wall Street’s Reaction To The Microsoft-Yahoo Search Deal: Not Good</title>
			<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/G0cRUCoJdyw/</link>
			<comments>http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/29/wall-streets-reaction-to-the-microsoft-yahoo-search-deal-not-good/#comments</comments>
			<pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2009 16:07:35 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Erick Schonfeld</dc:creator>
			
		<category><![CDATA[Company & Product Profiles]]></category>

		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>

		<category><![CDATA[Yahoo]]></category>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.techcrunch.com/?p=87966</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<img src="http://www.techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/07/yhoo-stock-chart-on-deal-215x85.jpg" width="215" height="85" />

Carol Bartz and Steve Ballmer are all smiles this morning with the signing of their long-awaited <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/29/microsoft-yahoo-search-deal-the-most-important-facts-and-some-opinion/">search deal,</a> but the <a href=" http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/29/bartz-on-bing-seearch-deal-everyone-wants-a-real-alternative-live-notes/">agreement</a> isn't going over so well on Wall Street.  Shares of Yahoo took a plunge this morning on the announcement and are <a href="http://finance.yahoo.com/echarts?s=yhoo">currently trading</a> at $15.31, down 11 percent from yesterday's close.  <a href="http://finance.yahoo.com/q?s=msft&#038;.yficrumb=FOQArQWgPuY">Microsoft shares</a> are flat.

Investors who were hoping for a large upfront payment and <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/05/27/bartz-wants-to-buy-social-and-video-startups-would-sell-yahoo-for-boatloads-of-money/">"boatloads of money"</a> were disappointed by the terms of the deal, which includes no upfront payment.  But that is short-sighted of investors because the actual deal ends up giving Yahoo a much bigger share of search revenues (88 percent) than the previous deal that was on the table last year.  It is actually a much better deal for Yahoo long-term if it works, and aligns its incentives closer to Microsoft's.  ]]></description>
					<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://cache0.techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/07/yhoo-stock-chart-on-deal.jpg"/></p>
<p>Carol Bartz and Steve Ballmer are all smiles this morning with the signing of their long-awaited <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/29/microsoft-yahoo-search-deal-the-most-important-facts-and-some-opinion/">search deal,</a> but the <a href=" http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/29/bartz-on-bing-seearch-deal-everyone-wants-a-real-alternative-live-notes/">agreement</a> isn&#8217;t going over so well on Wall Street.  Shares of Yahoo took a plunge this morning on the announcement and are <a href="http://finance.yahoo.com/echarts?s=yhoo">currently trading</a> at $15.31, down 11 percent from yesterday&#8217;s close.  <a href="http://finance.yahoo.com/q?s=msft&#038;.yficrumb=FOQArQWgPuY">Microsoft shares</a> are flat.</p>
<p>Investors who were hoping for a large upfront payment and <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/05/27/bartz-wants-to-buy-social-and-video-startups-would-sell-yahoo-for-boatloads-of-money/">&#8220;boatloads of money&#8221;</a> were disappointed by the terms of the deal, which includes no upfront payment.  But that is short-sighted of investors because the actual deal ends up giving Yahoo a much bigger share of search revenues (88 percent) than the previous deal that was on the table last year.  It is actually a much better deal for Yahoo long-term if it works, and aligns its incentives closer to Microsoft&#8217;s.  </p>
<p>If Yahoo were instead to realize more of the value of the deal upfront, it wouldn&#8217;t have as much reason to make the deal a success over time.  This is a10-year deal.  Making sure both sides are working towards the same goals for the next decade is pretty crucial, and a large upfront payment would have diminished that incentive because it would have come with a lower revenue-share for Yahoo on the backend.  Microsoft CEO Steve Ballmer said as much on the <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/29/bartz-on-bing-seearch-deal-everyone-wants-a-real-alternative-live-notes/">conference call</a> this morning when asked what the differnce was between this deal and the one offered last year.</p>
<blockquote><p>The deal last year was tailored more towards an investor than an operator. This deal is different, not better. Less upfront payment, and definitely a higher TAC rate.</p></blockquote>
<p>(The TAC (traffic acquisitions cost) rate is the percentage of search ad revenues Yahoo gets from the deal).  Whether or not Bartz had a choice in the matter, taking the higher TAC rate over a &#8220;boatload of cash&#8221; will be better for Yahoo in the long run.  Eventually, Yahoo&#8217;s investors will figure that out.</p>
<p><strong><em>Crunch Network</em></strong>:  <a href="http://www.mobilecrunch.com/">MobileCrunch</a><em> </em>Mobile Gadgets and Applications, Delivered Daily.</p>
<div><a href='http://d.techcrunch.com/ck.php?n=a8e452d3&amp;cb=221' target='_blank'><img src='http://d.techcrunch.com/avw.php?zoneid=38&amp;cb=591&amp;n=a8e452d3' border='0' alt='' /></a></div>
<div><a href='http://d.techcrunch.com/ck.php?n=a9e88cf5&amp;cb=1673' target='_blank'><img src='http://d.techcrunch.com/avw.php?zoneid=13&amp;cb=914&amp;n=a9e88cf5' border='0' alt='' /></a></div>


<p><a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/KtLag9gSvBwP9rhusI6MDHqg0gY/0/da"><img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/KtLag9gSvBwP9rhusI6MDHqg0gY/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"></img></a><br/>
<a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/KtLag9gSvBwP9rhusI6MDHqg0gY/1/da"><img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/KtLag9gSvBwP9rhusI6MDHqg0gY/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"></img></a></p><div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=G0cRUCoJdyw:EmX6aAJBAOo:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=G0cRUCoJdyw:EmX6aAJBAOo:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=G0cRUCoJdyw:EmX6aAJBAOo:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=G0cRUCoJdyw:EmX6aAJBAOo:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=G0cRUCoJdyw:EmX6aAJBAOo:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=G0cRUCoJdyw:EmX6aAJBAOo:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/G0cRUCoJdyw" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
						<wfw:commentRss>http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/29/wall-streets-reaction-to-the-microsoft-yahoo-search-deal-not-good/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
					<feedburner:origLink>http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/29/wall-streets-reaction-to-the-microsoft-yahoo-search-deal-not-good/</feedburner:origLink></item>
				<item>
			<title>Inside AP’s New News DRM System</title>
			<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/oFCz3qFC11o/</link>
			<comments>http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/29/inside-aps-new-news-drm-system/#comments</comments>
			<pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2009 16:05:03 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>John Biggs</dc:creator>
			
		<category><![CDATA[Company & Product Profiles]]></category>

		<category><![CDATA[A.P.]]></category>

		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.techcrunch.com/?p=87968</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<img src="http://www.techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/07/cp_1248883503_dzzdf-620x462-215x160.jpg" width="215" height="160" />
There has been some talk about the <a HREF="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/04/06/behind-the-aps-plan-to-become-the-webs-news-cop/">Associated Press' new system</a>, called hNews for some reason, for protecting its precious copywritten materials from bloggers, pirates, and pederasts. The system will include a DRM system that will make sure you can't cut and paste data from a browser to a blog post, thereby ensuring that no one can steal the AP's valuable, value-added content. As I recall similar systems were implemented by websites back in the days of AOL. They didn't work because you could just view the source code or, interestingly enough, take a screen shot.

The system works by putting something into a digital container and then sending to Google or whatever. This same system, as you recall, has prevented the rise of piracy in the music and movie arenas and must be applied to the written word before the Internet fails and we all resort to getting our news from "prophets" who will line major thoroughfares opining on things they believe happened, whether or not they are true. In short, we'll be stuck with cable news pundits.]]></description>
					<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="http://www.techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/07/cp_1248883503_dzzdf-620x462-215x160.jpg" width="215" height="160" />
There has been some talk about the <a HREF="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/04/06/behind-the-aps-plan-to-become-the-webs-news-cop/">Associated Press' new system</a>, called hNews for some reason, for protecting its precious copywritten materials from bloggers, pirates, and pederasts. The system will include a DRM system that will make sure you can't cut and paste data from a browser to a blog post, thereby ensuring that no one can steal the AP's valuable, value-added content. As I recall similar systems were implemented by websites back in the days of AOL. They didn't work because you could just view the source code or, interestingly enough, take a screen shot.

The system works by putting something into a digital container and then sending to Google or whatever. This same system, as you recall, has prevented the rise of piracy in the music and movie arenas and must be applied to the written word before the Internet fails and we all resort to getting our news from "prophets" who will line major thoroughfares opining on things they believe happened, whether or not they are true. In short, we'll be stuck with cable news pundits.
<p><a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/qunG5JIasT3iFyEmRoU8HMwhbzg/0/da"><img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/qunG5JIasT3iFyEmRoU8HMwhbzg/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"></img></a><br/>
<a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/qunG5JIasT3iFyEmRoU8HMwhbzg/1/da"><img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/qunG5JIasT3iFyEmRoU8HMwhbzg/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"></img></a></p><div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=oFCz3qFC11o:5HL41Bqla2E:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=oFCz3qFC11o:5HL41Bqla2E:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=oFCz3qFC11o:5HL41Bqla2E:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=oFCz3qFC11o:5HL41Bqla2E:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=oFCz3qFC11o:5HL41Bqla2E:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=oFCz3qFC11o:5HL41Bqla2E:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/oFCz3qFC11o" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
						<wfw:commentRss>http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/29/inside-aps-new-news-drm-system/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
					<feedburner:origLink>http://www.crunchgear.com/2009/07/29/aps-rights-management-drm-explained/</feedburner:origLink></item>
				<item>
			<title>Vudu Tries Plan B, Offers 1080p Streaming on LG TVs</title>
			<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/UiKSVgRE6wg/</link>
			<comments>http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/29/vudu-tries-plan-b-offers-1080p-streaming-on-lg-tvs/#comments</comments>
			<pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2009 13:54:47 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>John Biggs</dc:creator>
			
		<category><![CDATA[Company & Product Profiles]]></category>

		<category><![CDATA[LG]]></category>

		<category><![CDATA[Vudu]]></category>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.techcrunch.com/?p=87956</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<img src="http://www.techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/07/cp_1248875687_scaledlh50_front-215x158.jpg" width="215" height="158" />Vudu had a great run. The company made boxes you set up near your TV that could download stream HD video without glitches, a sort of <a href="http://www.crunchgear.com/search/netflix+roku">Netflix On Demand</a>, as it were, without the popularity.

Well, Vudu is teaming up with LG to offer Vudu streaming in their new LH50 and PS80 TVs which puts their position as one of the better and more promising hardware providers and video streaming services in serious doubt.]]></description>
					<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="http://www.techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/07/cp_1248875687_scaledlh50_front-215x158.jpg" width="215" height="158" />Vudu had a great run. The company made boxes you set up near your TV that could download stream HD video without glitches, a sort of <a href="http://www.crunchgear.com/search/netflix+roku">Netflix On Demand</a>, as it were, without the popularity.

Well, Vudu is teaming up with LG to offer Vudu streaming in their new LH50 and PS80 TVs which puts their position as one of the better and more promising hardware providers and video streaming services in serious doubt.
<p><a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/tHrvx8JLGumLVBnMmXMYMNFMCIk/0/da"><img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/tHrvx8JLGumLVBnMmXMYMNFMCIk/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"></img></a><br/>
<a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/tHrvx8JLGumLVBnMmXMYMNFMCIk/1/da"><img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/tHrvx8JLGumLVBnMmXMYMNFMCIk/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"></img></a></p><div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=UiKSVgRE6wg:07bQSFLGziQ:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=UiKSVgRE6wg:07bQSFLGziQ:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=UiKSVgRE6wg:07bQSFLGziQ:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=UiKSVgRE6wg:07bQSFLGziQ:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=UiKSVgRE6wg:07bQSFLGziQ:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=UiKSVgRE6wg:07bQSFLGziQ:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/UiKSVgRE6wg" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
						<wfw:commentRss>http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/29/vudu-tries-plan-b-offers-1080p-streaming-on-lg-tvs/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
					<feedburner:origLink>http://www.crunchgear.com/2009/07/29/vudu-drops-to-plan-b-offers-1080p-streaming-on-lg-tvs/</feedburner:origLink></item>
				<item>
			<title>Oops, @MarissaMayer Deletes Sensitive Tweet That Can Still Be Found</title>
			<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/8ZthQEjMsbo/</link>
			<comments>http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/29/oops-marrisamayer-deletes-sensitive-tweet-that-can-still-be-found/#comments</comments>
			<pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2009 13:45:36 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Robin Wauters</dc:creator>
			
		<category><![CDATA[Company & Product Profiles]]></category>

		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>

		<category><![CDATA[google]]></category>

		<category><![CDATA[google-voice]]></category>

		<category><![CDATA[iPhone]]></category>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.techcrunch.com/?p=87944</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<img src="http://www.techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/07/marrissa-twitter-215x98.png" width="215" height="98" />Google's <a href="http://www.crunchbase.com/person/marissa-mayer">Marissa Mayer</a> has discovered the 'delete' button on <a href="http://twitter.com">Twitter</a>, but much like you can find deleted web pages using Google cache search, you can also uncover removed tweets by using Twitter Search. So what did <a href="http://twitter.com/marissamayer">she tweet</a> that was so bad that it needed to be removed?

A link to a <a href="http://www.bbspot.com/News/2009/07/google-removes-apple.html">satirical article on BBspot</a> about the whole <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/27/apple-is-growing-rotten-to-the-core-and-its-likely-atts-fault/">Google Voice iPhone app removal brouhaha</a>, titled "Google Pulls Apple from Search Results". In it, an author of the comedy news site writes that Google has removed all search results leading to Apple.com from its index, and redirecting searches for "iPhone" and "app store" to the IMDb.com page for <em>Payback</em>.]]></description>
					<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://cache0.techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/07/marrissa-twitter.png" />Google&#8217;s <a href="http://www.crunchbase.com/person/marissa-mayer">Marissa Mayer</a> has discovered the &#8216;delete&#8217; button on <a href="http://twitter.com">Twitter</a>, but much like you can find deleted web pages using Google cache search, you can also uncover removed tweets by using Twitter Search. So what did <a href="http://twitter.com/marissamayer">she tweet</a> that was so bad that it needed to be removed?</p>
<p>A link to a <a href="http://www.bbspot.com/News/2009/07/google-removes-apple.html">satirical article on BBspot</a> about the whole <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/27/apple-is-growing-rotten-to-the-core-and-its-likely-atts-fault/">Google Voice iPhone app removal brouhaha</a>, titled &#8220;Google Pulls Apple from Search Results&#8221;. In it, an author of the comedy news site writes that Google has removed all search results leading to Apple.com from its index, and redirecting searches for &#8220;iPhone&#8221; and &#8220;app store&#8221; to the IMDb.com page for <em>Payback</em>.</p>
<p>Mayer gets quoted a couple of times in the piece as well: </p>
<blockquote><p>Google&#8217;s official explanation for removing Apple from its search results came from Vice-President in charge of search, Marissa Mayer, &#8220;Those search results duplicate a lot of the functionality of other sites. For example, people can find cell phones on many other sites. We just think this makes it easier for our users.&#8221;</p></blockquote>
<p>Pretty funny for much everyone, but for such a key Google employee to link to that article could be a bit offensive to some (both inside Google and Apple), hence the removal, probably. But it does show what she thinks about the whole thing, that she has a sense of humour, and which sites she tends to visit to get her news.</p>
<p><strong>Update:</strong> this is very reminiscent of <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/05/08/joking-or-not-official-or-not-facebook-needs-to-grow-up/">Randi Zuckerberg&#8217;s joke on Twitter</a> about possibly deleted a club and its bouncer&#8217;s pages from Facebook.</p>
<p><strong><em>Crunch Network</em></strong>:  <a href="http://www.mobilecrunch.com/">MobileCrunch</a><em> </em>Mobile Gadgets and Applications, Delivered Daily.</p>
<div><a href='http://d.techcrunch.com/ck.php?n=a8e452d3&amp;cb=16' target='_blank'><img src='http://d.techcrunch.com/avw.php?zoneid=38&amp;cb=263&amp;n=a8e452d3' border='0' alt='' /></a></div>
<div><a href='http://d.techcrunch.com/ck.php?n=a9e88cf5&amp;cb=1977' target='_blank'><img src='http://d.techcrunch.com/avw.php?zoneid=13&amp;cb=1921&amp;n=a9e88cf5' border='0' alt='' /></a></div>


<p><a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/9gR8dc1oSNFecUVaPVJSZYaqh9Q/0/da"><img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/9gR8dc1oSNFecUVaPVJSZYaqh9Q/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"></img></a><br/>
<a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/9gR8dc1oSNFecUVaPVJSZYaqh9Q/1/da"><img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/9gR8dc1oSNFecUVaPVJSZYaqh9Q/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"></img></a></p><div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=8ZthQEjMsbo:ttLeZWBiPOQ:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=8ZthQEjMsbo:ttLeZWBiPOQ:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=8ZthQEjMsbo:ttLeZWBiPOQ:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=8ZthQEjMsbo:ttLeZWBiPOQ:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=8ZthQEjMsbo:ttLeZWBiPOQ:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=8ZthQEjMsbo:ttLeZWBiPOQ:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/8ZthQEjMsbo" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
						<wfw:commentRss>http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/29/oops-marrisamayer-deletes-sensitive-tweet-that-can-still-be-found/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
					<feedburner:origLink>http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/29/oops-marrisamayer-deletes-sensitive-tweet-that-can-still-be-found/</feedburner:origLink></item>
				<item>
			<title>Bartz On Bing Search Deal: “Everyone Wants A Real Alternative.”  (Live Notes)</title>
			<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/Naw81cYw5nw/</link>
			<comments>http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/29/bartz-on-bing-seearch-deal-everyone-wants-a-real-alternative-live-notes/#comments</comments>
			<pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2009 12:40:54 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Erick Schonfeld</dc:creator>
			
		<category><![CDATA[Company & Product Profiles]]></category>

		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>

		<category><![CDATA[Yahoo]]></category>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.techcrunch.com/?p=87919</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<img src="http://www.techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/07/ballmer-bartz-215x143.jpg" width="215" height="143" />


Microsoft and Yahoo <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/29/microsoft-yahoo-search-deal-the-official-press-release/">announced</a> their <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/29/microsoft-yahoo-search-deal-the-most-important-facts-and-some-opinion/">search partnership</a> this morning. In a nutshell, Microsoft will power search technology for both companies, while Yahoo will take over ad sales.  Here are my notes from this morning's Yahoo-Microsoft conference call:

Carol Bartz: This is a great day for Yahoo. A game changer. benefits for Yahoo. half of all Internet users come to us, but face a formidable competitor in search. share investment expense to scale the market.  Our vision is to be center of people's lives online. We must do that by working on our own properties or working with others like Microsoft.

Only covers search and search advertising business. Self-serve advertising will go through Ad Center.  Yahoo will continue to integrate search in its properties but back-end technologies will be powered by Bing.

What this deal is really about is scale. Advertisers want an alternative that has scale.  Everyone wants a real alternative and advertisers are no different.  ]]></description>
					<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/07/ballmer-bartz.jpg"><img src="http://cache0.techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/07/ballmer-bartz.jpg" alt="ballmer-bartz" title="ballmer-bartz" width="500" height="333" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-87963" /></a></p>
<p>Microsoft and Yahoo <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/29/microsoft-yahoo-search-deal-the-official-press-release/">announced</a> their <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/29/microsoft-yahoo-search-deal-the-most-important-facts-and-some-opinion/">search partnership</a> this morning. In a nutshell, Microsoft will power search technology for both companies, while Yahoo will take over ad sales.  Here are my notes from this morning&#8217;s Yahoo-Microsoft conference call (I&#8217;ve bolded parts for emphasis):</p>
<p><strong>Carol Bartz</strong>: This is a great day for Yahoo. A game changer. benefits for Yahoo. half of all Internet users come to us, but face a formidable competitor in search. share investment expense to scale the market.  Our vision is to be center of people&#8217;s lives online. We must do that by working on our own properties or working with others like Microsoft.</p>
<p><strong>Only covers search and search advertising business. Self-serve advertising will go through Ad Center.  Yahoo will continue to integrate search in its properties but back-end technologies will be powered by Bing.</p>
<p>What this deal is really about is scale. Advertisers want an alternative that has scale.  Everyone wants a real alternative and advertisers are no different.</strong> </p>
<p><strong>Ballmer</strong>:  About creating efficiencies.  <strong>The search scale we will get for Bing will allow us to create greater innovation for searchers and advertisers.  </strong></p>
<p>Win-win agreement for MSFT and YHOO.  Both get more scale, advertisers get more scale, the whole industry will benefit.</p>
<p>Carol Bartz:  <strong>Terms of the agreement.  Gives MSFT a 10-year license to Yahoo&#8217;s core search technologies. will integrate into AdCenter, which will power both our search and theirs.  Display is separate. </strong> </p>
<p><strong>MSFT pays 88% TAC on Yahoo&#8217;s owned and operated sites for 5 years.  </strong></p>
<p><strong>Revenue will come down a bit because of revenue share, operating income will be $500M higher, costs $200M lower, operating cash flow $275M higher at full implementation.</strong></p>
<p>This deal won&#8217;t happen over night. We will work with regulators. <strong>Anticipate closing the deal by early 201</strong>0. Will begin with major markets including the U.S., transition to Bing in 3 to 6 months, transition from Panama to Ad Center will take 12 months. </p>
<p><strong>Q&#038;A</strong></p>
<p>Q: Why not add a display advertising component to the deal?  How big is the RPS [revenue per search] gap?</p>
<p>Bartz: <strong>On the display side we wanted to keep this as simple and straightforward as possible. </strong> </p>
<p>Ballmer: <strong>We are taking a big bite here</strong>. Search is more well-known when it comes to automation on the selling side. On RPS, I don&#8217;t expect a negative consequence on our P&#038;L, but a risk we are willing to take. [<em>Also antitrust concerns, which he doesn't mention</em>]</p>
<p>Bartz: This is more about making the outside world feel comfortable because we are very comfortable with [the RPS the deal will generate]</p>
<p>Q: <strong>You moved from a deal that would generate a boatload of cash to a deal with a boatload of value. Why no upfront fee?</strong></p>
<p>Bartz: <strong>What was really important to Yahoo was that we had a deal that flowed successfully through our P&#038;L.  What we really wanted was a significant TAC rate.  As far as we are concerned the boatload of cash is preserving our revenue line</strong></p>
<p>Ballmer: You take the current revenue mix Yahoo has, a certain RPS, we are guaranteeing that. If it is the same query mix and same market it ensures revenue only varies by the TAC amount and nothing else, that is a floor, not a ceiling..  </p>
<p>Q: Transition costs?</p>
<p>Ballmer: <strong>There will be two years of transition costs.</strong> Upside really comes as we improve the relevance of search ads. As we improve monetization on both Yahoo sites and MSFT sites, there is clearly upside in that.<strong> Our upside comes as execution builds. For us the investment will be a few hundred million over the next two years to get this to work.</strong></p>
<p>Q: How does this affect total CapEx?</p>
<p>Ballmer: Some additional CapEx, nothing that affects FY10 for us.  <strong>We have a plan where some Yahoo engineers over time may move over to Microsoft.</strong></p>
<p>Q:  What if any opposition will you face in Washington to make this all happen?</p>
<p>Ballmer:  <strong>We will face some opposition from a competitor who may not want more competition. Certainly we would expect the competitor to be aggressive</strong>. I think we have a good case for how this improves competition for consumers and the advertiser. We will be called on to present that case in Washington and Brussels.  </p>
<p>?: Will start filing process next week. Google has 78% of paid search. Don&#8217;t know of any instance where a company so dominant made antitrust objections to a deal.</p>
<p>Q: <strong>Any impact on jobs?</strong></p>
<p>Bartz: Y<strong>es, there are certainly many Yahoo search employees who will be asked to take jobs at MSFT.</strong> There will also be search employees [who get redeployed].<strong> Unfortunately there will be some redundancies in Yahoo.</strong> This is a transition over the next 2 and half years. Nothing will change until we get regulatory approval, but yes, there will be redundancies, but in the future.</p>
<p>Q: Do you have a number?</p>
<p>Bartz: That is in the planning. <strong>We have no numbers to announce at this time.</strong>  </p>
<p>Q: How much does this affect the place search takes in Yahoo&#8217;s services?</p>
<p>Ballmer: <strong>The way the deal was constructed, most complex part of the discussion, was to ensure that engineers on both sides could innovate around and about search around other things as much as the other company can, and to protect the privacy of the consumer that they deserve. During the last many months, the challenge was not just to work through the high-level financials but to work through these details.</strong></p>
<p>Q: How can Yahoo be innovative if MSFT takes over search technology?</p>
<p>Bartz: <strong>There is a lot of innovation that happens above the search result.</strong></p>
<p>Q: What does this mean for mobile?</p>
<p>Bartz: What we are very interested in is doubling down on the mobile experience to integrate search into that, to integrate our content. Being able to have integrated search is important and also frees us up to innovate on the other areas. Allows Yahoo to do want we do well, be the center of information, entertainment, friends and family.  </p>
<p>Q: You said what the TAC rate was for O&#038;O, but what is TAC rate when Yahoo sells on Bing.com?  What assumptions are you making for risk to affiliates (YHOO)?   How do you convince Google advertisers to run a multiple campaign.</p>
<p>Bartz: On Bing there is no TAC, that is MSFT&#8217;s revenue . . . </p>
<p>Ballmer: <strong>You don&#8217;t know when you sell a campaign where the keyword will show up. You are buying the keyword on both environments. </strong></p>
<p>Bartz: That is exactly right.  You are really selling the combined market.  On affiliates, it makes sense they would go straight to MSFT.  The small advertisers don&#8217;t want to learn three platforms. What is important is that there is scale. They know how to answer into the Google ad system.  We really expect we can provide a much better experience for this tail of advertisers and win them over.</p>
<p>Ballmer: The gap where we will be when we put our platforms together will be there, but it won&#8217;t be 800,000 [advertisers].  Google is something like 92% in Western Europe. At least there is a clear alternative choice.  </p>
<p>Q: How will Bing use Yahoo search code?</p>
<p>Ballmer: Our engineers know Bing and will build to that platform, but we wanted to make sure we could put together our expertise and code with Yahoo&#8217;s expertise and code.  We are very pleased it is not a rip and replace.</p>
<p>Bartz: On the paid search side, we are the provider for MSFT now in most of the international geographies. So there are both platforms to consider.  </p>
<p>Q: Innovations as part of the deal?</p>
<p>Ballmer: We have access to two of the best sets of technology. <strong>Do we think we will have better algorithms for relevance?  Yes we do. There is a feedback loop in search. the more searches you serve, the more you learn about what people click on. Scale drives knowledge.  There is a return to scale from seeing that much activity [that is more] than Yahoo or MSFT see independently.</strong></p>
<p>Bartz: We should talk about innovations on the ad sales side. <strong>Online advertising is in its pre-infancy.  All of that is enhanced because it is a bigger marketplace.</strong></p>
<p>Q:  <strong>Why is this deal better than the one MSFT had on the table last year?</strong></p>
<p>Bartz:  I&#8217;ve done some exploring of that. there is actually more fiction in the market than fact. The big difference is that it was perceived as more of an upfront payment and a lower TAC. That is not interesting for us. We feel this is a true partnership with the technology and selling.</p>
<p>Ballmer: <strong>The deal last year was tailored more towards an investor than an operator. This deal is different, not better. Less upfront payment, and definitely a higher TAC rate.</strong></p>
<p>Q: What pushed this through?</p>
<p>Bartz: Transferring paid search so people are comfortable with the platforms.  Like the proverbial snowball down the hill once it gained momentum.</p>
<p>Ballmer:<strong> It is not like we come here with a two-page term sheets. I think we have well over 100 pages to describe what we are doing. What we were spending our time on wasn&#8217;t the high-level principles.</strong></p>
<p>Q: Doing a partnership is harder</p>
<p>Bartz:  Sure it is. <strong>Dating is one thing, but having a partnership is another. We had to make sure we were committed</strong>. It is a distraction. We will put the right team in place to make the transition. Once we got to the point we believed it would be advantageous for us, we moved ahead.  That is what a partnership is.</p>
<p>Q: What will happen with other areas of search, Yahoo News, delicious, etc?</p>
<p>Bartz: When we talk about internal Yahoo search that is some of the innovation we are looking at doing.  Paid inclusion we will decide on later. We have full flexibility on what to do inside our site. That is the important thing, there is a lot of value there to add search to our properties.</p>
<p>Ballmer:  It was important to us to structure the deal to give Yahoo full flexibility [to add search to its services].</p>
<p>(Flickr photo via <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/yodelanecdotal/3768403423/in/set-72157621758388451">Yahoo</a>).  </p>
<p><strong><em>Crunch Network</em></strong>:  <a href="http://www.crunchgear.com">CrunchGear</a><em> </em>drool over the sexiest new gadgets and hardware.</p>
<div><a href='http://d.techcrunch.com/ck.php?n=a8e452d3&amp;cb=723' target='_blank'><img src='http://d.techcrunch.com/avw.php?zoneid=38&amp;cb=585&amp;n=a8e452d3' border='0' alt='' /></a></div>
<div><a href='http://d.techcrunch.com/ck.php?n=a9e88cf5&amp;cb=358' target='_blank'><img src='http://d.techcrunch.com/avw.php?zoneid=13&amp;cb=1336&amp;n=a9e88cf5' border='0' alt='' /></a></div>


<p><a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/oozpEuvXZZ0CbZsXYbuJ64sCLuw/0/da"><img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/oozpEuvXZZ0CbZsXYbuJ64sCLuw/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"></img></a><br/>
<a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/oozpEuvXZZ0CbZsXYbuJ64sCLuw/1/da"><img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/oozpEuvXZZ0CbZsXYbuJ64sCLuw/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"></img></a></p><div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=Naw81cYw5nw:X7CSuW8DDwI:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=Naw81cYw5nw:X7CSuW8DDwI:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=Naw81cYw5nw:X7CSuW8DDwI:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=Naw81cYw5nw:X7CSuW8DDwI:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=Naw81cYw5nw:X7CSuW8DDwI:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=Naw81cYw5nw:X7CSuW8DDwI:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/Naw81cYw5nw" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
						<wfw:commentRss>http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/29/bartz-on-bing-seearch-deal-everyone-wants-a-real-alternative-live-notes/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
					<feedburner:origLink>http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/29/bartz-on-bing-seearch-deal-everyone-wants-a-real-alternative-live-notes/</feedburner:origLink></item>
				<item>
			<title>Microsoft-Yahoo Search Deal: The Most Important Facts (And Some Opinion)</title>
			<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/PIk80lW6OnI/</link>
			<comments>http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/29/microsoft-yahoo-search-deal-the-most-important-facts-and-some-opinion/#comments</comments>
			<pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2009 12:18:16 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Robin Wauters</dc:creator>
			
		<category><![CDATA[Company & Product Profiles]]></category>

		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>

		<category><![CDATA[Yahoo]]></category>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.techcrunch.com/?p=87897</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<img src="http://www.techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/07/ms-yahoo1-215x65.png" width="215" height="65" />Now that the <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/29/microsoft-yahoo-search-deal-imminent-analysts-weigh-in/">search deal</a> struck between Microsoft and Yahoo has been officially confirmed by both companies, by means of a <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/29/microsoft-yahoo-search-deal-the-official-press-release/">press release</a> and a website dubbed <a href="http://www.choicevalueinnovation.com">ChoiceValueInnovation.com</a>, let's take a step back and analyze the most important tidbits from the announcement:

As expected, Microsoft will power Yahoo Search while Yahoo! will become the exclusive worldwide relationship sales force for both companies’ advertisers. 

This will have major repercussions for the online advertising industry, where both Microsoft and Yahoo are strongholds and carry a lot of weight. Likely, it will take months if not years to align these important businesses. As Carol Bartz indicated in the press release, on the flip side advertisers and publishers would benefit significantly from a unified platform and the promise of scalability allround. I believe this is indeed the core of being able to compete with both companies' dominant rival, Google.]]></description>
					<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="shot2" title="yahoo_microsoft" src="http://cache0.techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/07/ms-yahoo1.png" alt="yahoo_microsoft" />Now that the <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/29/microsoft-yahoo-search-deal-imminent-analysts-weigh-in/">search deal</a> struck between Microsoft and Yahoo has been officially confirmed by both companies, by means of a <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/29/microsoft-yahoo-search-deal-the-official-press-release/">press release</a> and a website dubbed <a href="http://www.choicevalueinnovation.com">ChoiceValueInnovation.com</a>, let&#8217;s take a step back and analyze the most important tidbits from the announcement:</p>
<p>As expected, Microsoft will power Yahoo Search while Yahoo! will become the exclusive worldwide relationship sales force for both companies’ advertisers. </p>
<p>This will have major repercussions for the online advertising industry, where both Microsoft and Yahoo carry a lot of weight. Likely, it will take months if not years to align these important businesses. On the flip side, as Yahoo CEO <a href="http://www.crunchbase.com/person/carol-bartz">Carol Bartz</a> indicated in the press release, advertisers and publishers would benefit significantly from a unified platform and the promise of scalability all around. I believe this is indeed the core advantage of the deal in terms of being able to compete with the dominant rival to both companies, Google.</p>
<p>Of course the companies didn&#8217;t spell out Google in the official announcements made this morning (except for a link on the <a href="http://ycorpblog.com/2009/07/29/what-our-microsoft-deal-means-to-you/">Yahoo blog post</a>), but which other company &#8220;dominates more than 70 percent of all search&#8221;?  We actually thought it was <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/15/bing-gains-some-search-share-from-yahoo/">more like 65%</a>, but the reality is that this difference in statistics isn&#8217;t nearly as important as the obvious fact that Google controls the large majority of search market share on one hand and even more of the advertising dollars that flow through search, on the other hand. Clearly, Microsoft desperately wants a piece of this cake, and it won&#8217;t settle for a small one.</p>
<p>Microsoft has shown it can compete in search by <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/05/31/go-bing-yourself-right-now/">releasing</a> <a href="http://bing.com">Bing</a>, which already has claimed its stake as a quality search engine that people <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/13/bing-reports-8-percent-visitor-growth-its-first-month-after-launch/">actually use</a> and <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/06/15/the-postman-always-bings-twice/">enjoy using</a> to boot.  It helps that it has boatloads of cash ready to market Bing aggressively, and you can make sure that they will, too. Furthermore, the companies claim the search deal and technology exchange can lead to more innovation in search, which I agree with wholeheartedly and encourage on multiple levels. If it effectively will eat away at Google&#8217;s core business by stealing significant market share organically remains to be seen, though.</p>
<p>One of the most apparent facts in the announcement that was not known beforehand by any blogs or news sites, is the longevity of the agreement: <em>10 years</em>, which is like an eternity in the Internet space. Microsoft will acquire an exclusive 10 year license to Yahoo’s core search technologies, which is basically the same as saying it just gained unparalleled access to the blueprint of Yahoo Search, something that can only lead to improvement of its Bing search engine. That and the fact that Bing will be the exclusive algorithmic search and paid search platform for Yahoo! sites confirms the notion that Sunnyvale has indeed <a href="http://searchengineland.com/its-finally-official-microsoft-yahoo-make-a-deal-yahoo-gives-up-on-search-23197">given up on search</a> in a big way.</p>
<p>Yahoo! will become the exclusive worldwide relationship sales force for both companies’ premium search advertisers. Self-serve advertising for both companies will be fulfilled by Microsoft’s AdCenter platform, and prices for all search ads will continue to be set by AdCenter’s automated auction process. That means there&#8217;s now Google AdWords vs. Microsoft AdCenter and Google AdSense vs. Microsoft PubCenter, and little else that matters in the search marketing arena. Take note, marketers.</p>
<p>Microsoft will pay traffic acquisition costs to Yahoo at an initial rate of 88% of search revenue generated on Yahoo’s owned and operated sites during the first 5 years of the agreement, and guarantee revenue per search in each country for the first 18 months following initial implementation in that country. This is huge, and it shows Redmond will continue to chase after the heart of Google, no matter how much money it takes. After those 18 month and 5 year periods, it&#8217;s unclear what will happen. Important to note is that Yahoo! will continue to syndicate its existing search affiliate partnerships.</p>
<p>Yahoo expects to fully implement the combined effort within 24 months following regulatory approval, which it hopes to gain in early 2010. The company estimates - based on current levels of revenue and operating expenses - that the agreement will provide a benefit to annual GAAP operating income of approximately $500 million and capital expenditure savings of approximately $200 million. Yahoo! also estimates that this agreement will provide a benefit to annual operating cash flow of approximately $275 million, something it sorely needs and which shareholders will be very happy about if it checks out eventually.</p>
<p>Already, Yahoo and Microsoft are fencing off regulatory investigation and criticism, stating clearly that they will be limiting the data shared between the companies to the &#8220;minimum necessary to operate and improve the combined search platform&#8221;, and restrict the use of search data shared between the companies.</p>
<p>What do you think: is this a win-win agreement for both Microsoft and Yahoo? How about users? Should Google be worried? Will the deal be approved at all?</p>
<p><strong><em>Crunch Network</em></strong>:  <a href="http://www.mobilecrunch.com/">MobileCrunch</a><em> </em>Mobile Gadgets and Applications, Delivered Daily.</p>
<div><a href='http://d.techcrunch.com/ck.php?n=a8e452d3&amp;cb=1561' target='_blank'><img src='http://d.techcrunch.com/avw.php?zoneid=38&amp;cb=1428&amp;n=a8e452d3' border='0' alt='' /></a></div>
<div><a href='http://d.techcrunch.com/ck.php?n=a9e88cf5&amp;cb=1202' target='_blank'><img src='http://d.techcrunch.com/avw.php?zoneid=13&amp;cb=1262&amp;n=a9e88cf5' border='0' alt='' /></a></div>


<p><a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/JUbuSqjhNTZVtFNazS3JW3EkG74/0/da"><img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/JUbuSqjhNTZVtFNazS3JW3EkG74/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"></img></a><br/>
<a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/JUbuSqjhNTZVtFNazS3JW3EkG74/1/da"><img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/JUbuSqjhNTZVtFNazS3JW3EkG74/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"></img></a></p><div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=PIk80lW6OnI:Br7DIBkU27Q:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=PIk80lW6OnI:Br7DIBkU27Q:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=PIk80lW6OnI:Br7DIBkU27Q:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=PIk80lW6OnI:Br7DIBkU27Q:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=PIk80lW6OnI:Br7DIBkU27Q:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=PIk80lW6OnI:Br7DIBkU27Q:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/PIk80lW6OnI" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
						<wfw:commentRss>http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/29/microsoft-yahoo-search-deal-the-most-important-facts-and-some-opinion/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
					<feedburner:origLink>http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/29/microsoft-yahoo-search-deal-the-most-important-facts-and-some-opinion/</feedburner:origLink></item>
				<item>
			<title>Microsoft-Yahoo Search Deal: The Official Press Release</title>
			<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/DZUqaH9yYmY/</link>
			<comments>http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/29/microsoft-yahoo-search-deal-the-official-press-release/#comments</comments>
			<pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2009 11:38:54 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Robin Wauters</dc:creator>
			
		<category><![CDATA[Company & Product Profiles]]></category>

		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>

		<category><![CDATA[Yahoo]]></category>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.techcrunch.com/?p=87882</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<img src="http://www.techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/07/yahoo_microsoft-215x138.png" width="215" height="138" />
<a href="http://microsoft.com">Microsoft</a> and <a href="http://yahoo.com">Yahoo</a> have now officially announced the search deal that has been <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/28/microsoft-yahoo-still-negotiating-deal-could-be-announced-any-time/">rumored</a> for <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/21/microsoftyahoo-search-today-not-so-fast/">long</a> and finally <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/29/microsoft-yahoo-search-deal-imminent-analysts-weigh-in/">confirmed</a> by us and other news outlets yesterday evening. 

Official press release (emphasis ours apart from title and subtitles) after the jump:]]></description>
					<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://cache0.techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/07/ms-yahoo.png" /><img class="shot2" title="yahoo_microsoft" src="http://cache0.techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/07/yahoo_microsoft.png" alt="yahoo_microsoft" width="225" height="145" /><br />
<a href="http://microsoft.com">Microsoft</a> and <a href="http://yahoo.com">Yahoo</a> have now officially announced the search deal that has been <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/28/microsoft-yahoo-still-negotiating-deal-could-be-announced-any-time/">rumored</a> for <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/21/microsoftyahoo-search-today-not-so-fast/">long</a> and finally <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/29/microsoft-yahoo-search-deal-imminent-analysts-weigh-in/">confirmed</a> by us and other news outlets yesterday evening. </p>
<p>Official press release (emphasis ours apart from title and subtitles):</p>
<blockquote><p><strong>Microsoft, Yahoo! Change Search Landscape</strong><br />
Global Deal Creates Better Choice for Consumers and Advertisers</p>
<p>SUNNYVALE, CA and REDMOND, WA — 29 July, 2009 — Yahoo! and Microsoft announced an agreement that will improve the Web search experience for users and advertisers, and deliver sustained innovation to the industry. In simple terms, <strong>Microsoft will now power Yahoo! search while Yahoo! will become the exclusive worldwide relationship sales force for both companies&#8217; premium search advertisers.</strong></p>
<p>For Web users and advertisers, this deal will accelerate the pace and breadth of innovation by combining both companies&#8217; complementary strengths and search platforms into a market competitor with the scale to fuel sustained development in search and search advertising. Users will find what they care about faster and with more personal relevance. Microsoft&#8217;s competitive search platforms will lead to more value for advertisers, better results for web publishers, and increased innovation and efficiency across the Internet.<br />
Under this agreement, Yahoo! will focus on its core business of providing consumers with great experiences with the world&#8217;s favorite online destinations and Web products.</p>
<p>&#8220;This agreement comes with boatloads of value for Yahoo!, our users, and the industry. And I believe it establishes the foundation for a new era of Internet innovation and development,&#8221; said Yahoo! CEO <a href="http://www.crunchbase.com/person/carol-bartz">Carol Bartz</a>. &#8220;Users will continue to experience search as a vital part of their Yahoo! experiences and will enjoy increased innovation thanks to the scale and resources this deal provides. <strong>Advertisers will also benefit from scale and enjoy greater ease of use and efficiencies working with a single platform and sales team for premium advertisers.</strong> Finally, this deal will help us increase our investments in priority areas in winning audience properties, display advertising capabilities, and mobile experiences.&#8221;</p>
<p>Providing a viable alternative to advertisers, this deal will combine Yahoo! and Microsoft search marketplaces so that advertisers <strong>no longer have to rely on one company that dominates more than 70 percent of all search.</strong> With the addition of Yahoo!&#8217;s search volume, Microsoft will achieve the size and scale required to unleash competition and innovation in the market, for consumers as well as advertisers.<br />
Microsoft CEO <a href="http://www.crunchbase.com/person/steve-ballmer">Steve Ballmer</a> said the agreement will provide Microsoft&#8217;s search engine, Bing, the scale necessary to more effectively compete, attracting more users and advertisers, which in turn will lead to more relevant ads and search results.</p>
<p>&#8220;Through this agreement with Yahoo!, we will create more innovation in search, better value for advertisers, and real consumer choice in a market currently dominated by a single company,&#8221; said Ballmer. &#8220;Success in search requires both innovation and scale. With our new Bing search platform, we&#8217;ve created breakthrough innovation and features. This agreement with Yahoo! will provide the scale we need to deliver even more rapid advances in relevancy and usefulness. <strong>Microsoft and Yahoo! know there&#8217;s so much more that search could be. This agreement gives us the scale and resources to create the future of search.</strong>&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;This deal fits the long-term strategic direction of Yahoo! to remain the world&#8217;s leading online media company and Carol Bartz has the full and unanimous support of the Yahoo! Board behind this deal,&#8221; said <a href="http://www.crunchbase.com/person/roy-bostock">Roy Bostock</a>, chairman, Yahoo! Inc. &#8220;This is a significant opportunity for us. Microsoft is an industry innovator in search, and it is a great opportunity for us to focus our investments in other areas critical to our future.&#8221;</p>
<p>The key terms of the agreement are as follows:</p>
<p>- The term of the agreement is <strong>10 years</strong>;</p>
<p>- Microsoft will acquire an <strong>exclusive 10 year license to Yahoo!&#8217;s core search technologies</strong>, and Microsoft will have the ability to integrate Yahoo! search technologies into its existing web search platforms;<br />
<strong>Microsoft&#8217;s Bing will be the exclusive algorithmic search and paid search platform for Yahoo! sites.</strong> Yahoo! will continue to use its technology and data in other areas of its business such as enhancing display advertising technology.</p>
<p>- <strong>Yahoo! will become the exclusive worldwide relationship sales force for both companies&#8217; premium search advertisers.</strong> Self-serve advertising for both companies will be fulfilled by Microsoft&#8217;s AdCenter platform, and prices for all search ads will continue to be set by AdCenter&#8217;s automated auction process.</p>
<p>- Each company will maintain <strong>its own separate display advertising business and sales force.</strong></p>
<p>- Yahoo! will innovate and &#8220;own&#8221; the user experience on Yahoo! properties, including the user experience for search, even though it will be powered by Microsoft technology.</p>
<p>- Microsoft will compensate Yahoo! through a <strong>revenue sharing agreement on traffic</strong> generated on Yahoo!&#8217;s network of both owned and operated (O&#038;O) and affiliate sites.</p>
<p>- <strong>Microsoft will pay traffic acquisition costs (TAC) to Yahoo! at an initial rate of 88% of search revenue generated on Yahoo!&#8217;s O&#038;O sites during the first 5 years of the agreement.</strong></p>
<p>- Yahoo! will continue to syndicate its existing search affiliate partnerships.</p>
<p>- <strong>Microsoft will guarantee Yahoo!&#8217;s O&#038;O revenue per search</strong> (RPS) in each country for the first 18 months following initial implementation in that country.</p>
<p>- At full implementation (expected to occur within 24 months following regulatory approval), Yahoo! estimates, based on current levels of revenue and current operating expenses, that this agreement will provide a benefit to <strong>annual GAAP operating income of approximately $500 million and capital expenditure savings of approximately $200 million. Yahoo! also estimates that this agreement will provide a benefit to annual operating cash flow of approximately $275 million.</strong></p>
<p>The agreement protects consumer privacy by <strong>limiting the data shared between the companies to the minimum necessary to operate</strong> and improve the combined search platform, and <strong>restricts the use of search data shared between the companies.</strong> The agreement maintains the industry-leading privacy practices that each company follows today.</p>
<p>The agreement does not cover each company&#8217;s web properties and products, email, instant messaging, display advertising, or any other aspect of the companies&#8217; businesses. In those areas, the companies will <strong>continue to compete vigorously</strong>.</p>
<p>The transaction will be subject to regulatory review. The agreement entered into today anticipates that the parties will enter into more detailed definitive agreements prior to closing. Microsoft and Yahoo! expect the agreement to be closely reviewed by the industry and government regulators, and welcome questions. <strong>The companies are hopeful that closing can occur in early 2010.</strong></p>
<p>The companies have established a website at <a href="http://www.choicevalueinnovation.com">http://www.choicevalueinnovation.com</a> to provide consumers, advertisers and publishers with additional information about the benefits of the agreement.</p>
<p><strong>Conference Call – 5:30 a.m. PDT, Wednesday, July 29</strong><br />
Yahoo! and Microsoft will host a conference call with Yahoo! CEO Carol Bartz and Microsoft CEO Steve Ballmer to discuss the agreement at 5:30 a.m. Pacific/8:30 a.m. Eastern Time today. </p>
<p>To listen to the call, please dial 1-866-515-2908 in the U.S. and Canada; +1-617-399-5122 international, reservation number: 47968026. A live webcast of the call can be accessed through Yahoo!’s Investor Relations website at http://yhoo.client.shareholder.com/results.cfm. </p>
<p>The companies have also established a website at http://www.choicevalueinnovation.com to provide consumers, advertisers and publishers with additional information about the benefits of the agreement. In addition, an archive of the webcast will be available through the same link. An audio replay of the call will be available for two weeks following the conference call by calling 1-888-286-8010 in the U.S. and Canada; +1-617-801-6888 international, reservation number: 91217610.</p>
<p><strong>Non-GAAP Financial Measures</strong><br />
This release refers to operating cash flow (operating income before depreciation, amortization of intangible assets, and stock-based compensation expense, or OCF), which is a non-GAAP financial measure. The most comparable GAAP measure is income from operations. The estimated annual OCF benefit of $275 million included in this press release is the estimated annual benefit in income from operations of $500 million less approximately $225 million of estimated annual savings in depreciation, amortization and stock-based compensation expense.</p></blockquote>
<p><strong><em>Crunch Network</em></strong>:  <a href="http://www.crunchgear.com">CrunchGear</a><em> </em>drool over the sexiest new gadgets and hardware.</p>
<div><a href='http://d.techcrunch.com/ck.php?n=a8e452d3&amp;cb=121' target='_blank'><img src='http://d.techcrunch.com/avw.php?zoneid=38&amp;cb=654&amp;n=a8e452d3' border='0' alt='' /></a></div>
<div><a href='http://d.techcrunch.com/ck.php?n=a9e88cf5&amp;cb=1581' target='_blank'><img src='http://d.techcrunch.com/avw.php?zoneid=13&amp;cb=55&amp;n=a9e88cf5' border='0' alt='' /></a></div>


<p><a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/QbmeEC-NNAqVG0KizR4SHBKNyzw/0/da"><img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/QbmeEC-NNAqVG0KizR4SHBKNyzw/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"></img></a><br/>
<a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/QbmeEC-NNAqVG0KizR4SHBKNyzw/1/da"><img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/QbmeEC-NNAqVG0KizR4SHBKNyzw/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"></img></a></p><div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=DZUqaH9yYmY:se8YybFI9PY:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=DZUqaH9yYmY:se8YybFI9PY:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=DZUqaH9yYmY:se8YybFI9PY:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=DZUqaH9yYmY:se8YybFI9PY:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=DZUqaH9yYmY:se8YybFI9PY:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=DZUqaH9yYmY:se8YybFI9PY:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/DZUqaH9yYmY" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
						<wfw:commentRss>http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/29/microsoft-yahoo-search-deal-the-official-press-release/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
					<feedburner:origLink>http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/29/microsoft-yahoo-search-deal-the-official-press-release/</feedburner:origLink></item>
				<item>
			<title>Microsoft-Yahoo Search Deal Imminent: Analysts Weigh In</title>
			<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/xPI_FGxGtv8/</link>
			<comments>http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/29/microsoft-yahoo-search-deal-imminent-analysts-weigh-in/#comments</comments>
			<pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2009 09:47:53 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Michael Arrington</dc:creator>
			
		<category><![CDATA[Company & Product Profiles]]></category>

		<category><![CDATA[Microsoft]]></category>

		<category><![CDATA[Yahoo]]></category>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.techcrunch.com/?p=87851</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<img src="http://www.techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/07/yahoo_microsoft-215x138.png" width="215" height="138" />As we first <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/28/microsoft-yahoo-still-negotiating-deal-could-be-announced-any-time/">reported yesterday</a>, Microsoft and Yahoo are on the verge of announcing a complicated search and search marketing alliance that will combine the no. 2 and no. 3 players in search into something that may have a chance of competing with Google (although combined they will still have less than half of Google's 65% or so search market share). The deal will be announced shortly after signing, and could come as early as today (Wednesday).

If the deal is completed it will close the 18-month long negotiation that began with a <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2008/02/01/wow-microsoft-offers-446-billion-to-acquire-yahoo/">$45 billion merger offer</a> on February 1, 2008. The details of the deal will determine the bump in Yahoo's share price, something <a href="http://www.google.com/finance?q=yahoo">investors</a> really desperately desire.

Here's what the deal may look like (from a Thomas Weisel Partners analyst report colorfully titled BingHoo! earlier this evening):
]]></description>
					<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-85045" title="yahoo_microsoft" src="http://cache0.techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/07/yahoo_microsoft.png" alt="yahoo_microsoft" width="225" height="145" />As we first <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/28/microsoft-yahoo-still-negotiating-deal-could-be-announced-any-time/">reported yesterday</a>, Microsoft and Yahoo are on the verge of announcing a complicated search and search marketing alliance that will combine the no. 2 and no. 3 players in search into something that may have a chance of competing with Google (although combined they will still have less than half of Google&#8217;s 65% or so search market share). The deal will be announced shortly after signing, and could come as early as today (Wednesday).</p>
<p>If the deal is completed it will close the 18-month long negotiation that began with a <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2008/02/01/wow-microsoft-offers-446-billion-to-acquire-yahoo/">$45 billion merger offer</a> on February 1, 2008. The details of the deal will determine the bump in Yahoo&#8217;s share price, something <a href="http://www.google.com/finance?q=yahoo">investors</a> really desperately desire.</p>
<p>Here&#8217;s what the deal may look like (from a Thomas Weisel Partners analyst report colorfully titled BingHoo! earlier this evening):</p>
<blockquote><p><strong>Deal (Finally) Inked:</strong> After a nearly three-year mating dance, Microsoft and Yahoo have agreed to a joint venture. The official announcement (hopefully with the financial implications) is expected tomorrow, July 29, the day before Microsoft’s annual analyst day.</p>
<p><strong>Bing becomes the algorithm:</strong> Importantly, Bing is expected to become the default search engine for Yahoo, as it has become across Microsoft’s network since its launch in June. By combining both companies’ engineering talent, search indexes and ad platforms, Microsoft believes it can improve its ability to drive innovation in emerging areas such as video, mobile, and online commerce; all areas where Google is currently focused. The combined Yahoo-Bing search would have 28% share in the U.S. according to comScore. But combining search indexes and reorganizing a global sales force across two companies is not a trivial matter and a distraction that Google can take advantage of. It is unclear what the cost savings would be to Yahoo. A year ago Yahoo management (headed by former CEO, Yang) indicated outsourcing all of search would yield a $750mn annual benefit. Given this deal covers only the algorithmic side and Yahoo has been cutting costs over the past year, we estimate the savings would be less than half that amount.</p>
<p><strong>Ad sales primarily owned by Yahoo:</strong> While details are still trickling out, it appears that Yahoo is slated to sell search inventory across both networks, capitalizing on Yahoo vertical strength in entertainment, finance and sports and Bing’s emerging strength in travel and retail. In addition Yahoo could gain the ability to sell display inventory across both networks along side search. The deal allows the parties to focus on core strengths: for Yahoo it’s selling and Microsoft it’s engineering.</p>
<p><strong>No Upfront Payment—Where’s that “boatload of cash?”:</strong> The reported deal does not include an upfront payment to Yahoo, a previous element of prior proposals, which may mute upside in Yahoo shares. Several critical details have yet to emerge: like the revenue share agreement and split levels, renewal terms of the partnership, cost savings and ultimate ownership of the data. For example, if the search deal is an 80/20 split, Yahoo would cede about $400mn of 2010 revenue to Microsoft. In addition, we estimate that Microsoft generates about $2bn in annual display revenue. If Yahoo got to sell half of that at an 80/20 split suggests Yahoo could see $200mn in incremental revenue.</p>
<p><strong>DoJ Scrutiny Risk:</strong> Importantly, the deal is likely to face a fair amount of interest from regulators regarding display advertising, which could delay the partnership by several months to several quarters.</p></blockquote>
<p>The bottom line is, no one expects any upfront payments to Yahoo. Revenue split estimates range from 80% - 110% to Yahoo (higher in the beginning), and there is likely a hefty guaranteed revenue component so assuage the Yahoo board of directors. </p>
<p>This is a much different search deal that <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2008/06/14/hey-microsoft-how-bout-we-do-that-first-deal-you-offered/">Microsoft offered Yahoo a year ago</a>. From our summary of that long-dead offer:</p>
<blockquote><p><strong>Microsoft’s Last Offer</strong></p>
<p>Microsoft last offered Yahoo a combination stock, asset and business deal that sources with knowledge of the situation summarize as follows:</p>
<p>Microsoft to acquire 16% of Yahoo’s outstanding stock from existing stockholders for $8 billion, or $35/share.</p>
<p>Microsoft to acquire all of Yahoo’s search and search marketing assets - servers, code, advertisers, third party publishers, intellectual property and employees (perhaps 3,000 of them) for $1 billion in cash plus a guaranteed CPC rate that is higher than what Yahoo can generate itself.</p>
<p>Yahoo gets increased search revenue from the deal over what they generate now, and get to remove people and operational costs of search.</p>
<p>Yahoo agrees not to touch the search or search marketing businesses directly ever again. All their searches are controlled by Microsoft.</p></blockquote>
<p>It&#8217;s also much different, and likely much less attractive, than the <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2008/06/12/googleyahoo-announcement-at-130-this-afternoon/">Google/Yahoo search deal</a> announced last summer and which was <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2008/11/05/google-pulls-the-plug-on-yahoo-advertising-deal/">terminated</a> before implementation.</p>
<p>We&#8217;ll analyze the actual deal terms as they are announced, but our guess is the likely outcome of this is one big complicated mess. The result: Google will take even more search share. Why these two companies don&#8217;t just merge is beyond me - everyone we&#8217;ve spoken with says everyone, on both sides of the table, would prefer a merger. Everyone, that is, except Microsoft CEO Steve Ballmer.</p>
<p><strong><em>Crunch Network</em></strong>:  <a href="http://www.crunchgear.com">CrunchGear</a><em> </em>drool over the sexiest new gadgets and hardware.</p>
<div><a href='http://d.techcrunch.com/ck.php?n=a8e452d3&amp;cb=1270' target='_blank'><img src='http://d.techcrunch.com/avw.php?zoneid=38&amp;cb=1173&amp;n=a8e452d3' border='0' alt='' /></a></div>
<div><a href='http://d.techcrunch.com/ck.php?n=a9e88cf5&amp;cb=1054' target='_blank'><img src='http://d.techcrunch.com/avw.php?zoneid=13&amp;cb=1792&amp;n=a9e88cf5' border='0' alt='' /></a></div>


<p><a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/ntAGW80jZMLq2z70jLt3GaAQPGc/0/da"><img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/ntAGW80jZMLq2z70jLt3GaAQPGc/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"></img></a><br/>
<a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/ntAGW80jZMLq2z70jLt3GaAQPGc/1/da"><img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/ntAGW80jZMLq2z70jLt3GaAQPGc/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"></img></a></p><div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=xPI_FGxGtv8:T3TTtIMme1o:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=xPI_FGxGtv8:T3TTtIMme1o:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=xPI_FGxGtv8:T3TTtIMme1o:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=xPI_FGxGtv8:T3TTtIMme1o:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=xPI_FGxGtv8:T3TTtIMme1o:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=xPI_FGxGtv8:T3TTtIMme1o:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/xPI_FGxGtv8" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
						<wfw:commentRss>http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/29/microsoft-yahoo-search-deal-imminent-analysts-weigh-in/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
					<feedburner:origLink>http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/29/microsoft-yahoo-search-deal-imminent-analysts-weigh-in/</feedburner:origLink></item>
				<item>
			<title>1-800-FLOWERS.COM Sets Up Shop Inside Facebook</title>
			<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/AbuirrJ4e3w/</link>
			<comments>http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/29/1-800-flowerscom-sets-up-shop-inside-facebook/#comments</comments>
			<pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2009 09:38:12 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Robin Wauters</dc:creator>
			
		<category><![CDATA[Company & Product Profiles]]></category>

		<category><![CDATA[1-800-flowers]]></category>

		<category><![CDATA[1-800-flowers.com]]></category>

		<category><![CDATA[Facebook]]></category>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.techcrunch.com/?p=87852</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<img src="http://www.techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/07/1-800-fb-215x68.png" width="215" height="68" />In another testament to the notion that <a href="http://facebook.com">Facebook</a> is quietly turning into the internet on top of the Internet, online flower retailer <a href="http://ww12.1800flowers.com/">1-800-Flowers.com</a> has launched an e-commerce store inside <a href="http://www.facebook.com/1800flowers?ref=search">its Facebook Page</a>.  

Registered users can now order all kinds of floral products from the popular florist and gift shop without ever leaving the social network.

1-800-FLOWERS is a bit of a pioneer when it comes to initiatives like this. In 1992 (!), the company was already fiddling with selling goods via the Internet, and two years later it became  the first merchant of any kind to transact on AOL. Now, at least according to the company, it's the first online retailer to launch a fully functional commercial storefront inside Facebook. Somehow, I doubt that statement rings true, but I couldn't immediately think of or find any other e-commerce outlets that can handle online orders from a to z inside Facebook.]]></description>
					<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://cache0.techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/07/1-800-fb.png" class="shot2" />In another testament to the notion that <a href="http://facebook.com">Facebook</a> is quietly turning into the internet on top of the Internet, online flower retailer <a href="http://ww12.1800flowers.com/">1-800-Flowers.com</a> has launched an e-commerce store inside <a href="http://www.facebook.com/1800flowers?ref=search">its Facebook Page</a>. </p>
<p>Registered users can now order all kinds of floral products from the popular florist and gift shop without ever leaving the social network.</p>
<p>1-800-FLOWERS is a bit of a pioneer when it comes to initiatives like this. In 1992 (!), the company was already fiddling with selling goods via the Internet, and two years later it became  the first merchant of any kind to transact on AOL. Now, at least according to the company, it&#8217;s the first online retailer to launch a fully functional commercial storefront inside Facebook. Somehow, I doubt that statement rings true, but I couldn&#8217;t immediately think of or find any other e-commerce outlets that can handle online orders from a to z inside Facebook.</p>
<p>Alas, when I did a search on Facebook for <a href="http://www.facebook.com/s.php?q=1-800-flowers&#038;init=quick">&#8220;1-800-flowers&#8221;</a>, the very first result was a group unambiguously called <a href="http://www.facebook.com/group.php?gid=10304716038&#038;ref=search">1-800-Flowers Sucks</a> and when I filtered down the results for Pages only the only result was one dubbed <a href="http://www.facebook.com/pages/1-800-flowers-screwed-u-2/122315346872?ref=search">1-800-flowers-screwed-u-2?</a> (albeit with 0 fans). I finally found the official Facebook Page when I added &#8220;.com&#8221; to the search query, but at first sight it seems currently people are using social media more often against the company than vice versa.</p>
<p>Anyway, this is what the company&#8217;s Facebook shop looks like:</p>
<p><img src="http://cache0.techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/07/1-800.png" /></p>
<p><img src="http://cache0.techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/07/1-800-2.png" /></p>
<p><img src="http://cache0.techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/07/1-800-3.png" /></p>
<p>1-800-FLOWERS.COM has teamed up with ad network / app developer <a href="http://alvenda.com/">Alvenda</a> to bring its store to a <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/15/facebooks-offical-user-count-now-250-million/">potentially massive audience</a> on Facebook (although only some 1530 people have become a fan of the florist shop&#8217;s Page so far). I&#8217;m told future versions of the store will integrate more robust social features, including birthday calendars and group gift giving options. </p>
<p>Currently, 1-800-FLOWERS accepts payment with all major credit cards, but it&#8217;s conceivable that it will be quick to implement Facebook&#8217;s upcoming <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/05/29/facebook-revs-up-for-payment-platform-with-updated-terms/">proprietary payment platform</a>, which is currently being <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/05/11/facebook-payment-platform-to-enter-testing-soon-only-7-months-late/">tested with a handful of developers</a>.</p>
<p>To conclude, a tip: when you become a fan of the retailer&#8217;s Facebook Page, you get a discount code. Happy flower shopping!</p>
<p><strong><em>Crunch Network</em></strong>:  <a href="http://www.mobilecrunch.com/">MobileCrunch</a><em> </em>Mobile Gadgets and Applications, Delivered Daily.</p>
<div><a href='http://d.techcrunch.com/ck.php?n=a8e452d3&amp;cb=300' target='_blank'><img src='http://d.techcrunch.com/avw.php?zoneid=38&amp;cb=1571&amp;n=a8e452d3' border='0' alt='' /></a></div>
<div><a href='http://d.techcrunch.com/ck.php?n=a9e88cf5&amp;cb=655' target='_blank'><img src='http://d.techcrunch.com/avw.php?zoneid=13&amp;cb=1446&amp;n=a9e88cf5' border='0' alt='' /></a></div>


<p><a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/32c3YDOWoFSLFoFG24C2R5rRdq8/0/da"><img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/32c3YDOWoFSLFoFG24C2R5rRdq8/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"></img></a><br/>
<a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/32c3YDOWoFSLFoFG24C2R5rRdq8/1/da"><img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/32c3YDOWoFSLFoFG24C2R5rRdq8/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"></img></a></p><div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=AbuirrJ4e3w:ChFqSY1R_v8:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=AbuirrJ4e3w:ChFqSY1R_v8:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=AbuirrJ4e3w:ChFqSY1R_v8:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=AbuirrJ4e3w:ChFqSY1R_v8:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=AbuirrJ4e3w:ChFqSY1R_v8:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=AbuirrJ4e3w:ChFqSY1R_v8:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/AbuirrJ4e3w" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
						<wfw:commentRss>http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/29/1-800-flowerscom-sets-up-shop-inside-facebook/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
					<feedburner:origLink>http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/29/1-800-flowerscom-sets-up-shop-inside-facebook/</feedburner:origLink></item>
				<item>
			<title>Booyah Society: Level Up in Life! with your iPhone</title>
			<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/dKFoPLNlYSs/</link>
			<comments>http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/29/booyah-society-level-up-in-life-with-your-iphone/#comments</comments>
			<pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2009 07:30:51 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Peter Ha</dc:creator>
			
		<category><![CDATA[CrunchGear]]></category>

		<category><![CDATA[mobilecrunch]]></category>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.techcrunch.com/?p=87703</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<img src="http://www.techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/07/cp_1248823526_picture-72-139x200.jpg" width="139" height="200" />So what is Booyah and what does it bring to the iPhone that no one else has done? Before we dive into that here’s a little background info on the Palo Alto, Calif.-based startup. Founded by three former videogame industry vets from Blizzard, Activision and Insomniac Games, Booyah looks to shake things up with real-life achievements for the iPhone (and iPod Touch). Booyah CEO Kevin Lee is an industry vet having worked on Ratchet and Clank, Diablo II, Resistance: Fall of Man before parting ways with Blizzard to launch Booyah with Brian Morrisroe and Sam Christiansen. Booyah’s main goal is “to motivate people to pursue their real-life passions while positively impacting themselves and the community around them.  It’s the first achievement system for life.”]]></description>
					<content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="http://www.techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/07/cp_1248823526_picture-72-139x200.jpg" width="139" height="200" />So what is Booyah and what does it bring to the iPhone that no one else has done? Before we dive into that here’s a little background info on the Palo Alto, Calif.-based startup. Founded by three former videogame industry vets from Blizzard, Activision and Insomniac Games, Booyah looks to shake things up with real-life achievements for the iPhone (and iPod Touch). Booyah CEO Kevin Lee is an industry vet having worked on Ratchet and Clank, Diablo II, Resistance: Fall of Man before parting ways with Blizzard to launch Booyah with Brian Morrisroe and Sam Christiansen. Booyah’s main goal is “to motivate people to pursue their real-life passions while positively impacting themselves and the community around them.  It’s the first achievement system for life.”
<p><a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/oA5ZiTS9UVxagVJy0wWWtfalWaM/0/da"><img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/oA5ZiTS9UVxagVJy0wWWtfalWaM/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"></img></a><br/>
<a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/oA5ZiTS9UVxagVJy0wWWtfalWaM/1/da"><img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/oA5ZiTS9UVxagVJy0wWWtfalWaM/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"></img></a></p><div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=dKFoPLNlYSs:dPkxcOT_NpM:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=dKFoPLNlYSs:dPkxcOT_NpM:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=dKFoPLNlYSs:dPkxcOT_NpM:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=dKFoPLNlYSs:dPkxcOT_NpM:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=dKFoPLNlYSs:dPkxcOT_NpM:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=dKFoPLNlYSs:dPkxcOT_NpM:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/dKFoPLNlYSs" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
						<wfw:commentRss>http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/29/booyah-society-level-up-in-life-with-your-iphone/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
					<feedburner:origLink>http://www.mobilecrunch.com/2009/07/28/booyah-society-level-up-in-life-via-the-iphone/</feedburner:origLink></item>
				<item>
			<title>YC-Funded HighlightCam Makes It Easy To Remotely Watch Babies, Pets And Burglars</title>
			<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/oW298irD5jc/</link>
			<comments>http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/28/yc-funded-highlightcam-makes-it-easy-to-remotely-watch-babies-pets-and-burglars/#comments</comments>
			<pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2009 06:16:18 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>MG Siegler</dc:creator>
			
		<category><![CDATA[Company & Product Profiles]]></category>

		<category><![CDATA[highlightcam]]></category>

		<category><![CDATA[Y-Combinator]]></category>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.techcrunch.com/?p=87839</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<img src="http://www.techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/07/picture-1212.png" width="210" height="96" />Live video monitoring systems are great — except for the fact that someone actually has to be watching for them to be of much use. Even if that doesn't mean watching it live, that means pouring over hours of footage that likely contains a lot of the same thing: Nothing. And that's why <a href="http://highlightcam.com/">HighlightCam</a> is cool. It condenses video down to just moments where there is actual activity.

It does this by watching for changes in video streams, which is to say that it looks for motion happening within the video. When it senses something, it knows to remember that portion of the video. And, if you set it up to do so, it can also send an email to you to let you know there is activity currently happening on the video stream. You can probably dream up a bunch of uses for something like this, but the obvious ones are monitoring babies from other room, watching your pets when you're away, and yes, watching to make sure no one is breaking into your house.]]></description>
					<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-87840" title="picture-1212" src="http://cache0.techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/07/picture-1212.png" alt="picture-1212" width="210" height="96" />Live video monitoring systems are great — except for the fact that someone actually has to be watching for them to be of much use. Even if that doesn&#8217;t mean watching it live, that means pouring over hours of footage that likely contains a lot of the same thing: Nothing. And that&#8217;s why <a href="http://highlightcam.com/">HighlightCam</a> is cool. It condenses video down to just moments where there is actual activity.</p>
<p>It does this by watching for changes in video streams, which is to say that it looks for motion happening within the video. When it senses something, it knows to remember that portion of the video. And, if you set it up to do so, it can also send an email to you to let you know there is activity currently happening on the video stream. You can probably dream up a bunch of uses for something like this, but the obvious ones are monitoring babies from other room, watching your pets when you&#8217;re away, and yes, watching to make sure no one is breaking into your house.</p>
<p>This sort of technology has only existed up until now in high-end security systems for big commercial buildings, we&#8217;re told. But HighlightCam does this at a fraction of the cost. To use it, you simply have to set up a webcam and then visit the HighlightCam site. The service is entirely browser-based. And you don&#8217;t even need an account to start using it (though you will need one to access recordings later).</p>
<p>If you want to see it in action, <a href="http://justin.tv">Justin.tv</a> has been using it for their <a href="http://highlightcam.com/justin.tv/">pets section</a>, and it was a part of their <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/26/justintv-opens-its-api-for-free-hopes-live-video-will-explode/">recent API launch</a>.</p>
<p>The <a href="http://www.ycombinator.com/">Y Combinator</a>-funded HighlighCam makes use of the freemium model. With the free version you get the core features including the ability to use any webcam and e-mail notifications. But the main limitation is that your recorded videos are only stored for 24 hours. With the <a href="http://highlightcam.com/about/#premium">premium version</a> (which is $8.99 a month), videos are archived for 2 weeks, and you get higher resolution recordings, no ads on the site and the ability to download recorded videos.</p>
<p>I think we definitely need to set this up for the TechCrunch <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/crunchcam/">CrunchCam</a>. Most of the time when I&#8217;m not in the office and I tune in, I just see <a href="http://www.crunchbase.com/person/jason-kincaid">Jason</a> and <a href="http://www.crunchbase.com/person/leena-rao">Leena</a> diligently typing away with absolutely no perceivable motion occuring. It&#8217;d be great to get an alert for the 15 minutes a day when there is actually something going on, like Segway jousting.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-87841" title="picture-147" src="http://cache0.techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/07/picture-147-630x272.png" alt="picture-147" width="630" height="272" /></p>
<p><strong><em>Crunch Network</em></strong>:  <a href="http://www.crunchbase.com">CrunchBase</a><em> </em>the free database of technology companies, people, and investors</p>
<div><a href='http://d.techcrunch.com/ck.php?n=a8e452d3&amp;cb=1957' target='_blank'><img src='http://d.techcrunch.com/avw.php?zoneid=38&amp;cb=1239&amp;n=a8e452d3' border='0' alt='' /></a></div>
<div><a href='http://d.techcrunch.com/ck.php?n=a9e88cf5&amp;cb=405' target='_blank'><img src='http://d.techcrunch.com/avw.php?zoneid=13&amp;cb=178&amp;n=a9e88cf5' border='0' alt='' /></a></div>


<p><a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/L4TcnG43pnC8luO2EWguEerUOrU/0/da"><img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/L4TcnG43pnC8luO2EWguEerUOrU/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"></img></a><br/>
<a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/L4TcnG43pnC8luO2EWguEerUOrU/1/da"><img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/L4TcnG43pnC8luO2EWguEerUOrU/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"></img></a></p><div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=oW298irD5jc:P53QNjG0pBQ:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=oW298irD5jc:P53QNjG0pBQ:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=oW298irD5jc:P53QNjG0pBQ:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=oW298irD5jc:P53QNjG0pBQ:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=oW298irD5jc:P53QNjG0pBQ:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=oW298irD5jc:P53QNjG0pBQ:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/oW298irD5jc" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
						<wfw:commentRss>http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/28/yc-funded-highlightcam-makes-it-easy-to-remotely-watch-babies-pets-and-burglars/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
					<feedburner:origLink>http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/28/yc-funded-highlightcam-makes-it-easy-to-remotely-watch-babies-pets-and-burglars/</feedburner:origLink></item>
				<item>
			<title>Larger Than Life Prints: Because Giant Custom Stickers Make Everything Better</title>
			<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/M6FQc5oGyzA/</link>
			<comments>http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/28/larger-than-life-prints-because-giant-custom-stickers-make-everything-better/#comments</comments>
			<pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2009 04:04:12 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Jason Kincaid</dc:creator>
			
		<category><![CDATA[Company & Product Profiles]]></category>

		<category><![CDATA[ltlprints]]></category>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.techcrunch.com/?p=87806</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.ltlprints.com/start"><img src="http://www.techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/07/bigdonut-215x172.png" width="215" height="172" /></a>Earlier this afternoon, the TechCrunch office got some new additions: a collection of massive stickers, ranging from giant TechCrunch logos (you can see them on the <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/crunchcam/">CrunchCam</a>) to various animals, a big donut, and even a surfing alien.  They come from a new startup called <a href="http://LTLprints.com">Larger Than Life Prints</a>, which is best described as a <a href="http://www.cafepress.com">CafePress</a> or <a href="http://www.zazzle.com">Zazzle</a> for humongous stickers.  The company allows users to design their own oversized wall graphics, which can then be ordered in one-off runs or sold to other visitors through an integrated store.

The site is still fairly new, but's already beginning to attract some top talent, including <a href="http://www.ltlprints.com/susankare">Susan Kare</a>, who is famous for designing the on-screen graphics of the original Macintosh computer and many of Facebook's popular virtual gifts.  LTL Prints is featuring many of these artists in a collection of '<a href="http://www.ltlprints.com/start">big wall art</a>', which includes art curated by the Start Soma Art Gallery.
]]></description>
					<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.ltlprints.com/start"><img src="http://cache0.techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/07/bigdonut.png" class="shot2"/></a>Earlier this afternoon, the TechCrunch office got some new additions: a collection of massive stickers, ranging from giant TechCrunch logos (you can see them on the <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/crunchcam/">CrunchCam</a>) to various animals, a big donut, and even a surfing alien.  They come from a new startup called <a href="http://LTLprints.com">Larger Than Life Prints</a>, which is best described as a <a href="http://www.cafepress.com">CafePress</a> or <a href="http://www.zazzle.com">Zazzle</a> for humongous stickers.  The company allows users to design their own oversized wall graphics, which can then be ordered in one-off runs or sold to other visitors through an integrated store.</p>
<p>The site is still fairly new, but&#8217;s already beginning to attract some top talent, including <a href="http://www.ltlprints.com/susankare">Susan Kare</a>, who is famous for designing the on-screen graphics of the original Macintosh computer and many of Facebook&#8217;s popular virtual gifts.  LTL Prints is featuring many of these artists in a collection of &#8216;<a href="http://www.ltlprints.com/start">big wall art</a>&#8216;, which includes art curated by the Start Soma Art Gallery.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s hard to really get excited about stickers, but these are actually pretty impressive.  They&#8217;re made out of a study fabric-based paper that&#8217;s really hard to tear (we tried), and it can also be applied many times on various surfaces, like walls and glass.   You can roll the sticker up in a ball, and it will pull apart without any lasting damage.  Contrast that with most other large stickers, which are typically made of vinyl, and it becomes clear that these are truly some high grade stickers.</p>
<p>Prices for the stickers range from $20 for a 2ft sticker to $165 for a massive 7 ft tall sticker.  From there you&#8217;re free to charge higher prices if you sell your sticker in the site&#8217;s integrated marketplace.<br />
<img src="http://cache0.techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/07/robotoguy.png"/></p>
<p><strong><em>Crunch Network</em></strong>:  <a href="http://www.crunchbase.com">CrunchBase</a><em> </em>the free database of technology companies, people, and investors</p>
<div><a href='http://d.techcrunch.com/ck.php?n=a8e452d3&amp;cb=1830' target='_blank'><img src='http://d.techcrunch.com/avw.php?zoneid=38&amp;cb=78&amp;n=a8e452d3' border='0' alt='' /></a></div>
<div><a href='http://d.techcrunch.com/ck.php?n=a9e88cf5&amp;cb=1093' target='_blank'><img src='http://d.techcrunch.com/avw.php?zoneid=13&amp;cb=1847&amp;n=a9e88cf5' border='0' alt='' /></a></div>


<p><a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/dX6I57XqMpBBvEIvmUVTJZ6qx58/0/da"><img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/dX6I57XqMpBBvEIvmUVTJZ6qx58/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"></img></a><br/>
<a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/dX6I57XqMpBBvEIvmUVTJZ6qx58/1/da"><img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/dX6I57XqMpBBvEIvmUVTJZ6qx58/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"></img></a></p><div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=M6FQc5oGyzA:st2JJaxlWcw:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=M6FQc5oGyzA:st2JJaxlWcw:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=M6FQc5oGyzA:st2JJaxlWcw:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=M6FQc5oGyzA:st2JJaxlWcw:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=M6FQc5oGyzA:st2JJaxlWcw:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=M6FQc5oGyzA:st2JJaxlWcw:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/M6FQc5oGyzA" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
						<wfw:commentRss>http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/28/larger-than-life-prints-because-giant-custom-stickers-make-everything-better/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
					<feedburner:origLink>http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/28/larger-than-life-prints-because-giant-custom-stickers-make-everything-better/</feedburner:origLink></item>
				<item>
			<title>Exclusive: Former MySpace CEO Chris DeWolfe Raising Money For New Venture</title>
			<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/JCc4Jo8_oTU/</link>
			<comments>http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/28/exclusive-former-myspace-ceo-chris-dewolfe-raising-money-for-new-venture/#comments</comments>
			<pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2009 03:04:53 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Michael Arrington</dc:creator>
			
		<category><![CDATA[Company & Product Profiles]]></category>

		<category><![CDATA[MySpace]]></category>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.techcrunch.com/?p=87804</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<img src="http://www.techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/07/cp_1248836693_18178v5-max-250x250-140x200.jpg" width="140" height="200" />Just three months ago MySpace cofounder and CEO <a href="http://www.crunchbase.com/person/chris-dewolfe">Chris DeWolfe</a> found out he was being <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/04/21/news-corp-exploring-myspace-ceo-options/">abruptly</a> and <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/04/24/news-corp-pulls-the-trigger-owen-van-vatta-now-runs-myspace/">rudely</a> replaced by <a href="http://www.crunchbase.com/person/owen-van-natta">Owen Van Natta</a>. So what does the guy who built the biggest site on the Internet from scratch do next? He raises a big pile of money, that's what.

We've confirmed that DeWolfe has been pitching a number of private equity funds to raise up to $100 million for a roll up of an Internet industry vertical. In exchange for confirmation we've agreed to keep exactly what that vertical is confidential for now. But at least two funds, both with significantly more than $1 billion to work with, are interested. DeWolfe, as is his style, won't comment on the fundraising.

It's not surprising that there is such strong interest. Few executives have been able to grow a company from zero to 1,700 employees and $800 million or so in revenue. In <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/01/24/myspacebook/">just five years</a>. DeWolfe may be <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2008/08/08/the-perks-of-being-the-myspace-cofounder-include-apparently-paris-hilton/">eccentric</a> but he's also <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2008/09/08/tc50-myspace-ceo-chris-dewolfe-says-95-percent-of-ad-revenues-comes-from-9-countries-announces-new-google-gears-project/">clearly</a> one hell of a business man and entrepreneur. And there is no one in the world with his connections and experience in both the geeky Internet world and flashy Hollywood scene.]]></description>
					<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src='http://www.crunchbase.com/assets/images/resized/0001/8178/18178v5-max-250x250.jpg'class="snap_nopreview shot2" alt="" />Just three months ago <a href="http://www.crunchbase.com/company/myspace">MySpace</a> cofounder and CEO <a href="http://www.crunchbase.com/person/chris-dewolfe">Chris DeWolfe</a> found out he was being <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/04/21/news-corp-exploring-myspace-ceo-options/">abruptly</a> and <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/04/24/news-corp-pulls-the-trigger-owen-van-vatta-now-runs-myspace/">rudely</a> replaced by <a href="http://www.crunchbase.com/person/owen-van-natta">Owen Van Natta</a>. So what does the guy who built the biggest site on the Internet from scratch do next? He raises a big pile of money, that&#8217;s what.</p>
<p>We&#8217;ve confirmed that DeWolfe has been pitching a number of private equity funds to raise up to $100 million for a roll up of an Internet industry vertical. In exchange for confirmation we&#8217;ve agreed to keep exactly what that vertical is confidential for now. But at least two funds, both with significantly more than $1 billion to work with, are interested. DeWolfe, as is his style, won&#8217;t comment on the fundraising.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s not surprising that there is such strong interest. Few executives have been able to grow a company from zero to 1,700 employees and $800 million or so in revenue. In <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/01/24/myspacebook/">just five years</a>. DeWolfe may be <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2008/08/08/the-perks-of-being-the-myspace-cofounder-include-apparently-paris-hilton/">eccentric</a> but he&#8217;s also <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2008/09/08/tc50-myspace-ceo-chris-dewolfe-says-95-percent-of-ad-revenues-comes-from-9-countries-announces-new-google-gears-project/">clearly</a> one hell of a business man and entrepreneur. And there is no one in the world with his connections and experience in both the geeky Internet world and flashy Hollywood scene.</p>
<p>Case in point - a couple of funds I called today to see if they&#8217;d been pitched yet eagerly asked for an introduction. I suggested they add him as a <a href="http://www.facebook.com/home.php#/profile.php?id=729696328&#038;hiq=chris%2Cdewolfe&#038;ref=search">friend</a> on Facebook.</p>
<p><strong><em>Crunch Network</em></strong>:  <a href="http://www.crunchbase.com">CrunchBase</a><em> </em>the free database of technology companies, people, and investors</p>
<div><a href='http://d.techcrunch.com/ck.php?n=a8e452d3&amp;cb=342' target='_blank'><img src='http://d.techcrunch.com/avw.php?zoneid=38&amp;cb=1070&amp;n=a8e452d3' border='0' alt='' /></a></div>
<div><a href='http://d.techcrunch.com/ck.php?n=a9e88cf5&amp;cb=1767' target='_blank'><img src='http://d.techcrunch.com/avw.php?zoneid=13&amp;cb=1065&amp;n=a9e88cf5' border='0' alt='' /></a></div>


<p><a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/J09iCy0yy4Rf6FiffunvZ-GgqLQ/0/da"><img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/J09iCy0yy4Rf6FiffunvZ-GgqLQ/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"></img></a><br/>
<a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/J09iCy0yy4Rf6FiffunvZ-GgqLQ/1/da"><img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/J09iCy0yy4Rf6FiffunvZ-GgqLQ/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"></img></a></p><div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=JCc4Jo8_oTU:wilh_IATEHI:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=JCc4Jo8_oTU:wilh_IATEHI:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=JCc4Jo8_oTU:wilh_IATEHI:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=JCc4Jo8_oTU:wilh_IATEHI:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=JCc4Jo8_oTU:wilh_IATEHI:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=JCc4Jo8_oTU:wilh_IATEHI:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/JCc4Jo8_oTU" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
						<wfw:commentRss>http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/28/exclusive-former-myspace-ceo-chris-dewolfe-raising-money-for-new-venture/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
					<feedburner:origLink>http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/28/exclusive-former-myspace-ceo-chris-dewolfe-raising-money-for-new-venture/</feedburner:origLink></item>
				<item>
			<title>New Twitter Homepage Goes Live With Search Front And Center</title>
			<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/sZjedfRupik/</link>
			<comments>http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/28/new-twitter-homepage-goes-live-with-search-front-and-center/#comments</comments>
			<pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2009 01:41:51 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>MG Siegler</dc:creator>
			
		<category><![CDATA[Company & Product Profiles]]></category>

		<category><![CDATA[Twitter]]></category>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.techcrunch.com/?p=87773</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<img src="http://www.techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/07/picture-316-630x420-215x143.png" width="215" height="143" />Twitter has just rolled out the new version of its <a href="http://twitter.com">homepage</a> that new potential users and users who are not logged in will see. The design has been completely overhauled from the previous version which was fairly cluttered (see it at the bottom of the page). This new version is sleek and features trending topics by the minute, hour and day.

Most importantly, the new version features search functionality front and center. This way people who aren't even Twitter users yet can search for things being said on the service. And results are nicely placed on the same page below the main area.

You'll also notice that when you click on any of the popular topics, a description of why that topic is being featured appears along the top of the search results. This is something that is very helpful, as quite a few trending topics seem to make no sense on the surface. It looks like Twitter is using the third-party service <a href="http://www.whatthetrend.com/">What The Trend?</a> to populate these descriptions.]]></description>
					<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-87795" title="picture-99" src="http://cache0.techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/07/picture-99.png" alt="picture-99" width="269" height="102" />Twitter has just rolled out the new version of its <a href="http://twitter.com">homepage</a> that new potential users and users who are not logged in will see. The design has been completely overhauled from the previous version which was fairly cluttered (see it at the bottom of the page). This new version is sleek and features trending topics by the minute, hour and day.</p>
<p>Most importantly, the new version features search functionality front and center. This way people who aren&#8217;t even Twitter users yet can search for things being said on the service. And results are nicely placed on the same page below the main area.</p>
<p>You&#8217;ll also notice that when you click on any of the popular topics, a description of why that topic is being featured appears along the top of the search results. This is something that is very helpful, as quite a few trending topics seem to make no sense on the surface. It looks like Twitter is using the third-party service <a href="http://www.whatthetrend.com/">What The Trend?</a> to populate these descriptions.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s important to note that nothing has changed about Twitter&#8217;s UI and functionality for those who are logged in. This is simply part of Twitter&#8217;s goal to make the service more accessible and obvious to new users, as well as increase engagement, and the use of search/trends. The bigger goal is to make it easier for businesses to use Twitter, which will allow the service to finally make some money. It&#8217;s <a href="http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/23/the-launch-of-twitter-101-step-one-of-the-business-plan-is-imminent/">new Twitter 101 area</a> is another of the initial steps in that direction.</p>
<p>Find screenshots below of both the new main page and the old version. As well as what the new main page search results look like.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-87774" title="picture-316" src="http://cache0.techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/07/picture-316-630x420.png" alt="picture-316" width="630" height="420" /></p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-87776" title="54257v1" src="http://cache0.techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/07/54257v1-630x555.png" alt="54257v1" width="630" height="555" /></p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-87779" title="picture-514" src="http://cache0.techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/07/picture-514-630x642.png" alt="picture-514" width="630" height="642" /></p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-87789" title="picture-711" src="http://cache0.techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/07/picture-711-630x423.png" alt="picture-711" width="630" height="423" /></p>
<p><strong>Update</strong>: And <a href="http://blog.twitter.com/2009/07/new-front-page.html">here&#8217;s Twitter&#8217;s post</a> on the new homepage. Here&#8217;s the key blurb:</p>
<blockquote><p>The open and timely exchange of information will have a positive impact on the world and Twitter has a role to play. We have a lot of work to do when it comes to the quality of our search results and trend analysis but repositioning the product to focus more on discovery is an important first step in presenting Twitter to a wider audience of folks around the world who are eager to start engaging with new people, ideas, opinions, events, and sources of information.</p>
<p>We&#8217;ll likely continue to make changes to the Twitter home page as we respond to feedback and ideas. We&#8217;re eager to see if encouraging a sense of wonder and discovery leads to a better first impression of Twitter.</p></blockquote>
<p><strong>Update 2</strong>: It also looks like Twitter is using this new homepage search interface to highlight some of the lesser-used search operators, like the &#8220;:)&#8221; symbol for results with &#8220;positive attitude.&#8221;</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-87797" title="picture-108" src="http://cache0.techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/07/picture-108-630x210.png" alt="picture-108" width="630" height="210" /></p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-87799" title="picture-1114" src="http://cache0.techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/07/picture-1114-630x310.png" alt="picture-1114" width="630" height="310" /></p>
<p><strong>Update 3</strong>: As Adobe&#8217;s Ryan Stewart <a href="http://twitter.com/ryanstewart/status/2901744792">notes</a> on Twitter, this homepage change seems like it could be a fairly big shot across the bow of Google. After all, if everyone now visiting twitter.com sees search front and center, it&#8217;s pretty clear that the product is being positioned as a major player in the search game. It will be interesting to see Twitter&#8217;s next step, which undoubtedly will include another homepage redesign to match this new Twitter home screen. Will we also see the search box more prominently featured there?</p>
<div class="cbw snap_nopreview">
<div class="cbw_header"><script src="http://www.crunchbase.com/javascripts/widget.js" type="text/javascript"></script></p>
<div class="cbw_header_text"><a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.crunchbase.com/">CrunchBase Information</a></div>
</div>
<div class="cbw_content">
<div class="cbw_subheader"><a href="http://www.crunchbase.com/company/twitter">Twitter</a></div>
<div class="cbw_subcontent"><script src="http://www.crunchbase.com/cbw/company/twitter.js" type="text/javascript"></script></div>
<div class="cbw_footer">Information provided by <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.crunchbase.com/">CrunchBase</a></div>
</div>
</div>
<p><strong><em>Crunch Network</em></strong>:  <a href="http://www.crunchboard.com">CrunchBoard</a><em> </em>because it&#8217;s time for you to find a new Job2.0</p>
<div><a href='http://d.techcrunch.com/ck.php?n=a8e452d3&amp;cb=1655' target='_blank'><img src='http://d.techcrunch.com/avw.php?zoneid=38&amp;cb=125&amp;n=a8e452d3' border='0' alt='' /></a></div>
<div><a href='http://d.techcrunch.com/ck.php?n=a9e88cf5&amp;cb=401' target='_blank'><img src='http://d.techcrunch.com/avw.php?zoneid=13&amp;cb=1215&amp;n=a9e88cf5' border='0' alt='' /></a></div>


<p><a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/AcAr8hQoubtp7cXkZg81wFLYiAI/0/da"><img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/AcAr8hQoubtp7cXkZg81wFLYiAI/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"></img></a><br/>
<a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/AcAr8hQoubtp7cXkZg81wFLYiAI/1/da"><img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/AcAr8hQoubtp7cXkZg81wFLYiAI/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"></img></a></p><div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=sZjedfRupik:PE-Fl5UEfuU:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=sZjedfRupik:PE-Fl5UEfuU:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=sZjedfRupik:PE-Fl5UEfuU:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=sZjedfRupik:PE-Fl5UEfuU:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=sZjedfRupik:PE-Fl5UEfuU:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=sZjedfRupik:PE-Fl5UEfuU:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/sZjedfRupik" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
						<wfw:commentRss>http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/28/new-twitter-homepage-goes-live-with-search-front-and-center/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
					<feedburner:origLink>http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/28/new-twitter-homepage-goes-live-with-search-front-and-center/</feedburner:origLink></item>
				<item>
			<title>YC-Funded RethinkDB: A MySQL Storage Engine Built From The Ground Up For Solid State Drives</title>
			<link>http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/Techcrunch/~3/XmrxpFGp5GY/</link>
			<comments>http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/28/yc-funded-rethinkdb-a-mysql-storage-engine-built-from-the-ground-up-for-ssds/#comments</comments>
			<pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2009 00:58:55 +0000</pubDate>
			<dc:creator>Jason Kincaid</dc:creator>
			
		<category><![CDATA[Company & Product Profiles]]></category>

		<category><![CDATA[rethinkdb]]></category>

		<category><![CDATA[Y-Combinator]]></category>
			<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.techcrunch.com/?p=87550</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<a href="http://www.rethinkdb.com"><img src="http://www.techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/07/rethinkdblogo-215x51.png" width="215" height="51" /></a>It's been a long time coming, but the computer industry is finally making headway in the switch from old-fashioned, platter based hard drives to the solid state drives (SSDs) found in iPhones and many other electronics.  The benefits are obvious: unlike their platter-based counterparts, SSDs have no moving parts, and they're also significantly faster for many tasks.  Unfortunately most software, both server-side and otherwise, has been optimized for the older drives and the physical limitations that come with them.  <a href="http://www.rethinkdb.com">RethinkDB</a> is a new startup that's looking to capitalize on this problem by building a storage engine for mySQL databases that's fully optimized for SSD drives, bringing with it large speed boosts and a number of features sure to catch the eye of many developers.

The company, which is part of the latest batch of <a href="http://www.ycombinator.com">Y Combinator</a>-funded startups, is in fairly early stages (it started developing the product only two months ago), but it's already making some substantial headway in the features it can offer. ]]></description>
					<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.rethinkdb.com"><img src="http://cache0.techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/07/rethinkdblogo.png" class="shot2"/></a>It&#8217;s been a long time coming, but the computer industry is finally making headway in the switch from old-fashioned, platter based hard drives to the solid state drives (SSDs) found in iPhones and many other electronics.  The benefits are obvious: unlike their platter-based counterparts, SSDs have no moving parts, and they&#8217;re also significantly faster for many tasks.  Unfortunately most software, both server-side and otherwise, has been optimized for the older drives and the physical limitations that come with them.  <a href="http://www.rethinkdb.com">RethinkDB</a> is a new startup that&#8217;s looking to capitalize on this problem by building a storage engine for mySQL databases that&#8217;s fully optimized for SSD drives, bringing with it large speed boosts and a number of features sure to catch the eye of many developers.</p>
<p>The company, which is part of the latest batch of <a href="http://www.ycombinator.com">Y Combinator</a>-funded startups, is in fairly early stages (it started developing the product only two months ago), but it&#8217;s already making some substantial headway in the features it can offer.  Among these are live schema changes, which allow developers to make significant modifications to their database structure without having to go through complex sync and backup procedures.  It also offers lock-free concurrency, which means users will be able to read from the database even while other users are writing to it.  And it&#8217;s an append-only database, which means developers can quickly recover in the event of a system failure.</p>
<p><img src="http://cache0.techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/07/rethinkdb.png"/></p>
<p>RethinkDB is also taking a relatively novel approach to its development, at least as far as database storage is concerned.  It&#8217;s following the &#8220;release early, release often&#8221; mantra, which it&#8217;s kicking off with the release of an early <a href="http://www.rethinkdb.com/wiki/">developer pre-alpha</a>, which you can download and try out for free (the company says that implementing the software is quite easy because of the way MySQL handles storage engines).  However, given that you&#8217;re going to be using this to manage your data, it is absolutely vital that you use this for testing purposes only — make sure you have any crucial data stored elsewhere.  The company hopes to use developer input over the next few months to improve the product up until its release.  </p>
<p>RethinkDB plans to have its commercial product out the door in the next six months, with an enterprise-level pricing structure that charges on a per-CPU basis (with support included).</p>
<p><strong><em>Crunch Network</em></strong>:  <a href="http://www.crunchbase.com">CrunchBase</a><em> </em>the free database of technology companies, people, and investors</p>
<div><a href='http://d.techcrunch.com/ck.php?n=a8e452d3&amp;cb=1553' target='_blank'><img src='http://d.techcrunch.com/avw.php?zoneid=38&amp;cb=1603&amp;n=a8e452d3' border='0' alt='' /></a></div>
<div><a href='http://d.techcrunch.com/ck.php?n=a9e88cf5&amp;cb=477' target='_blank'><img src='http://d.techcrunch.com/avw.php?zoneid=13&amp;cb=1675&amp;n=a9e88cf5' border='0' alt='' /></a></div>


<p><a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/q22Pb6YyDbM-1j9q0El0kpQ-wwM/0/da"><img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/q22Pb6YyDbM-1j9q0El0kpQ-wwM/0/di" border="0" ismap="true"></img></a><br/>
<a href="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/q22Pb6YyDbM-1j9q0El0kpQ-wwM/1/da"><img src="http://feedads.g.doubleclick.net/~at/q22Pb6YyDbM-1j9q0El0kpQ-wwM/1/di" border="0" ismap="true"></img></a></p><div class="feedflare">
<a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=XmrxpFGp5GY:nYB5kMBxJrM:2mJPEYqXBVI"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=2mJPEYqXBVI" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=XmrxpFGp5GY:nYB5kMBxJrM:dnMXMwOfBR0"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=dnMXMwOfBR0" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=XmrxpFGp5GY:nYB5kMBxJrM:D7DqB2pKExk"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?i=XmrxpFGp5GY:nYB5kMBxJrM:D7DqB2pKExk" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=XmrxpFGp5GY:nYB5kMBxJrM:7Q72WNTAKBA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=7Q72WNTAKBA" border="0"></img></a> <a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?a=XmrxpFGp5GY:nYB5kMBxJrM:yIl2AUoC8zA"><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~ff/Techcrunch?d=yIl2AUoC8zA" border="0"></img></a>
</div><img src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/Techcrunch/~4/XmrxpFGp5GY" height="1" width="1"/>]]></content:encoded>
						<wfw:commentRss>http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/28/yc-funded-rethinkdb-a-mysql-storage-engine-built-from-the-ground-up-for-ssds/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
					<feedburner:origLink>http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/07/28/yc-funded-rethinkdb-a-mysql-storage-engine-built-from-the-ground-up-for-ssds/</feedburner:origLink></item>
			</channel>
</rss>
